<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Security on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2025 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 11 Kafka Authorization</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</guid><description>In the previous posts, we discussed how to implement client authentication by TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) and SASL authentication. One of the key benefits of client authentication is achieving user access control. Kafka ships with a pluggable, out-of-the box authorization framework, which is configured with the authorizer.class.name property in the server configuration and stores Access Control Lists (ACLs) in the cluster metadata (either Zookeeper or the KRaft metadata log). In this post, we will discuss how to configure Kafka authorization with Java and Python client examples while SASL is kept for client authentication.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/featured.png" length="458848" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 10 SASL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) authentication to improve security. It enforces two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers. Client authentication can also be enabled by Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL), and we will discuss how to implement SASL authentication with Java and Python client examples in this post.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Management App Part 3 Kafka Connect Part 4 Producer and Consumer Part 5 Glue Schema Registry Part 6 Kafka Connect with Glue Schema Registry Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry Part 8 SSL Encryption Part 9 SSL Authentication Part 10 SASL Authentication (this post) Part 11 Kafka Authorization Certificate Setup As we will leave Kafka communication to remain encrypted, we need to keep the components for SSL encryption.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/featured.png" length="471947" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 9 SSL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to configure TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) encryption with Java and Python client examples. SSL encryption is a one-way verification process where a server certificate is verified by a client via SSL Handshake. To improve security, we can add client authentication either by enforcing two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers (SSL authentication). Or we can choose a separate authentication mechanism, which is typically Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/featured.png" length="471471" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 8 SSL Encryption</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</guid><description>By default, Apache Kafka communicates in PLAINTEXT, which means that all data is sent without being encrypted. To secure communication, we can configure Kafka clients and other components to use Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption. Note that TLS is also referred to Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) or TLS/SSL. SSL is the predecessor of TLS, and has been deprecated since June 2015. However, it is used in configuration and code instead of TLS for historical reasons.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/featured.png" length="469311" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>