<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Terraform on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in Terraform on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2026 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manage EMR on EKS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</guid><description>Amazon EMR on EKS is a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on EKS. While eksctl is popular for working with Amazon EKS clusters, it has limitations when it comes to building infrastructure that integrates multiple AWS services. Also, it is not straightforward to update EKS cluster resources incrementally with it. On the other hand Terraform can be an effective tool for managing infrastructure that includes not only EKS and EMR virtual clusters but also other AWS resources.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/featured.png" length="67936" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Your Development on AWS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</guid><description>When I wrote my data lake demo series (part 1, part 2 and part 3) recently, I used an Aurora PostgreSQL, MSK and EMR cluster. All of them were deployed to private subnets and dedicated infrastructure was created using CloudFormation. Using the infrastructure as code (IaC) tool helped a lot, but it resulted in creating 7 CloudFormation stacks, which was a bit harder to manage in the end. Then I looked into how to simplify building infrastructure and managing resources on AWS and decided to use Terraform instead.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/featured.png" length="46253" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>