<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Data Streaming on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/data-streaming/</link><description>Recent content in Data Streaming on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/data-streaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy Python Stream Processing App on Kubernetes - Part 2 Beam Pipeline on Flink Runner</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this post, we develop an <a href="https://beam.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Beam<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> pipeline using the <a href="https://beam.apache.org/documentation/sdks/python/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Python SDK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and deploy it on an <a href="https://flink.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> cluster via the <a href="https://beam.apache.org/documentation/runners/flink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink Runner<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. Same as <a href="/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1">Part I</a>, we deploy a Kafka cluster using the <a href="https://strimzi.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Strimzi Operator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> on a <a href="https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">minikube<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> cluster as the pipeline uses <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Kafka<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> topics for its data source and sink. Then, we develop the pipeline as a Python package and add the package to a custom Docker image so that Python user code can be executed externally. For deployment, we create a Flink session cluster via the <a href="https://nightlies.apache.org/flink/flink-kubernetes-operator-docs-main/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flink Kubernetes Operator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, and deploy the pipeline using a Kubernetes job. Finally, we check the output of the application by sending messages to the input Kafka topic using a Python producer application.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/featured.png" length="58020" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Deploy Python Stream Processing App on Kubernetes - Part 1 PyFlink Application</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://nightlies.apache.org/flink/flink-kubernetes-operator-docs-main/docs/concepts/overview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flink Kubernetes Operator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> acts as a control plane to manage the complete deployment lifecycle of Apache Flink applications. With the operator, we can simplify deployment and management of Python stream processing applications. In this series, we discuss how to deploy a PyFlink application and Python Apache Beam pipeline on the <a href="https://beam.apache.org/documentation/runners/flink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flink Runner<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> on Kubernetes. In Part 1, we first deploy a Kafka cluster on a <a href="https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">minikube<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> cluster as the source and sink of the PyFlink application are Kafka topics. Then, the application source is packaged in a custom Docker image and deployed on the minikube cluster using the Flink Kubernetes Operator. Finally, the output of the application is checked by sending messages to the input Kafka topic using a Python producer application.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/featured.png" length="64457" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon MSK can be configured as an <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lambda/latest/dg/with-msk.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">event source<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> of a Lambda function. Lambda internally polls for new messages from the event source and then synchronously invokes the target Lambda function. With this feature, we can develop a Kafka consumer application in serverless environment where developers can focus on application logic. In this lab, we will discuss how to create a Kafka consumer using a Lambda function.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/featured.png" length="138986" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-30-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-30-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-6/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://kafka.apache.org/documentation/#connect" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kafka Connect<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems. It makes it simple to quickly define connectors that move large collections of data into and out of Kafka. In this lab, we will discuss how to create a data pipeline that ingests data from a Kafka topic into a DynamoDB table using the <a href="https://camel.apache.org/camel-kafka-connector/3.20.x/reference/connectors/camel-aws-ddb-sink-kafka-sink-connector.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Camel DynamoDB sink connector<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-30-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-6/featured.png" length="113252" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>The value of data can be maximised when it is used without delay. With Apache Flink, we can build streaming analytics applications that incorporate the latest events with low latency. In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that writes accumulated taxi rides data into an OpenSearch cluster. It aggregates the number of trips/passengers and trip durations by vendor ID for a window of 5 seconds. The data is then used to create a chart that monitors the status of taxi rides in the OpenSearch Dashboard.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/featured.png" length="112340" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that exports Kafka topic messages into a S3 bucket. The app enriches the records by adding a new column using a user defined function and writes them via the <a href="https://nightlies.apache.org/flink/flink-docs-release-1.17/docs/connectors/table/filesystem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FileSystem SQL connector<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. This allows us to achieve a simpler architecture compared to the <a href="https://catalog.us-east-1.prod.workshops.aws/workshops/2300137e-f2ac-4eb9-a4ac-3d25026b235f/en-US/lab-3-kdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">original lab<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> where the records are sent into Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose, enriched by a separate Lambda function and written to a S3 bucket afterwards. While the records are being written to the S3 bucket, a Glue table will be created to query them on Amazon Athena.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/featured.png" length="160359" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that reads records from S3 and sends them into a Kafka topic. A custom pipeline Jar file will be created as the Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM, and it will be demonstrated how to execute the app in a Flink cluster deployed on Docker as well as locally as a typical Python app. We can assume the S3 data is static metadata that needs to be joined into another stream, and this exercise can be useful for data enrichment.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/featured.png" length="139114" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Benefits and Opportunities of Stateful Stream Processing</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-02-stateful-stream-processing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-02-stateful-stream-processing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stream processing technology is becoming more and more popular with companies big and small because it provides superior solutions for many established use cases such as data analytics, ETL, and transactional applications, but also facilitates novel applications, software architectures, and business opportunities. Beginning with traditional data infrastructures and application/data development patterns, this post introduces stateful stream processing and demonstrates to what extent it can improve the traditional development patterns. A consulting company can partner with her clients on their journeys of adopting stateful stream processing, and it can bring huge opportunities. Those opportunities are summarised at the end.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-02-stateful-stream-processing/featured.png" length="244920" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 5 Deploy Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In the previous post, we discussed how to develop a data pipeline from Apache Kafka into OpenSearch locally using Docker. The pipeline will be deployed on AWS using <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon MSK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/features/msk-connect/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon MSK Connect<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/opensearch-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon OpenSearch Service<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> using <a href="https://www.terraform.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Terraform<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> in this post. First the infrastructure will be deployed that covers a Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Virtual Private Network (VPN) server, MSK Cluster and OpenSearch domain. Then Kafka source and sink connectors will be deployed on MSK Connect, followed by performing quick data analysis.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/featured.png" length="85575" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this lab, we will create a Kafka producer application using <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Lambda<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, which sends fake taxi ride data into a Kafka topic on <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon MSK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. A configurable number of the producer Lambda function will be invoked by an <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eventbridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon EventBridge<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> schedule rule. In this way we are able to generate test data concurrently based on the desired volume of messages.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/featured.png" length="138560" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 4 Develop Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://opensearch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenSearch<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is a popular search and analytics engine and its use cases cover log analytics, real-time application monitoring, and clickstream analysis. OpenSearch can be deployed on its own or via <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/opensearch-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon OpenSearch Service<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Kafka<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is a distributed event store and stream-processing platform, and it aims to provide a unified, high-throughput, low-latency platform for handling real-time data feeds. On AWS, Apache Kafka can be deployed via <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK)<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/featured.png" length="61820" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Building Apache Flink Applications in Python</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://developer.confluent.io/courses/flink-java/overview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Building Apache Flink Applications in Java<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is a course to introduce <a href="https://flink.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> through a series of hands-on exercises, and it is provided by <a href="https://www.confluent.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Confluent<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. Utilising the <a href="https://nightlies.apache.org/flink/flink-docs-release-1.17/docs/dev/datastream/overview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flink DataStream API<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, the course develops three Flink applications that populate multiple source data sets, collect them into a standardised data set, and aggregate it to produce usage statistics. As part of learning the Flink DataStream API in Pyflink, I converted the Java apps into Python equivalent while performing the course exercises in Pyflink. This post summarises the progress of the conversion and shows the final output.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/featured.png" length="154736" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://catalog.us-east-1.prod.workshops.aws/workshops/2300137e-f2ac-4eb9-a4ac-3d25026b235f/en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Real Time Streaming with Amazon Kinesis<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is an AWS workshop that helps users build a streaming analytics application on AWS. Incoming events are stored in a number of streams of the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-streams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Kinesis Data Streams<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> service, and various other AWS services and tools are used to process and analyse data.</p>
<p><a href="https://kafka.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Kafka<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform, and it stores incoming events in topics. As part of learning real time streaming analytics on AWS, we can rebuild the analytics applications by replacing the Kinesis streams with Kafka topics. As an introduction, this post compares the workshop architecture with the updated architecture of this series. The labs of the updated architecture will be implemented in subsequent posts.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/featured.png" length="138141" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 2 Deployment via AWS Managed Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This series aims to help those who are new to <a href="https://flink.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2023/08/amazon-managed-service-apache-flink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> by re-implementing a simple fraud detection application that is discussed in an AWS workshop titled <a href="https://catalog.us-east-1.prod.workshops.aws/workshops/ad026e95-37fd-4605-a327-b585a53b1300/en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Kafka and DynamoDB for real time fraud detection<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. In part 1, I demonstrated how to develop the application locally, and the app will be deployed via <em>Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink</em> in this post.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/featured.png" length="66221" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 3 AWS Managed Flink and MSK</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this series of posts, we discuss a Flink (Pyflink) application that reads/writes from/to Kafka topics. In the previous posts, I demonstrated a Pyflink app that targets a local Kafka cluster as well as a Kafka cluster on Amazon MSK. The app was executed in a virtual environment as well as in a local Flink cluster for improved monitoring. In this post, the app will be deployed via <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2023/08/amazon-managed-service-apache-flink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, which is the easiest option to run Flink applications on AWS.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="74618" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 2 Local Flink and MSK</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this series of posts, we discuss a Flink (Pyflink) application that reads/writes from/to Kafka topics. In part 1, an app that targets a local Kafka cluster was created. In this post, we will update the app by connecting a Kafka cluster on Amazon MSK. The Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM and the app has additional jar dependency. As <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2023/08/amazon-managed-service-apache-flink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> does not allow you to specify multiple pipeline jar files, we have to build a custom Uber Jar that combines multiple jar files. Same as part 1, the app will be executed in a virtual environment as well as in a local Flink cluster for improved monitoring with the updated pipeline jar file.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="64005" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 1 Local Flink and Local Kafka</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://flink.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few. On AWS, we can deploy a Flink application via <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-analytics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA)<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/emr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon EMR<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon EKS<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. Among those, KDA is the easiest option as it provides the underlying infrastructure for your Apache Flink applications.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="55960" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://flink.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few. On AWS, we can deploy a Flink application via <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-analytics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA)<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/emr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon EMR<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon EKS<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. Among those, KDA is the easiest option as it provides the underlying infrastructure for your Apache Flink applications.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/featured.png" length="72929" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 3 Deploy Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>As part of investigating how to utilize Kafka Connect effectively for AWS services integration, I demonstrated how to develop the <a href="https://camel.apache.org/camel-kafka-connector/latest/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Camel DynamoDB sink connector<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> using Docker in <a href="/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2">Part 2</a>. Fake order data was generated using the <a href="https://github.com/awslabs/amazon-msk-data-generator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK Data Generator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> source connector, and the sink connector was configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table. In this post, I will illustrate how to deploy the data ingestion applications using <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon MSK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/features/msk-connect/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK Connect<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="76240" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 2 Develop Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1">Part 1</a>, we reviewed Kafka connectors focusing on AWS services integration. Among the available connectors, the suite of <a href="https://camel.apache.org/camel-kafka-connector/latest/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Camel Kafka connectors<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and the <a href="https://github.com/awslabs/kinesis-kafka-connector" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kinesis Kafka connector<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> from the AWS Labs can be effective for building data ingestion pipelines on AWS. In this post, I will illustrate how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker. Fake order data will be generated using the <a href="https://github.com/awslabs/amazon-msk-data-generator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK Data Generator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> source connector, and the sink connector will be configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="87044" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 1 Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-streams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Kinesis Data Streams<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK)<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> are two managed streaming services offered by AWS. Many resources on the web indicate Kinesis Data Streams is better when it comes to integrating with AWS services. However, it is not necessarily the case with the help of Kafka Connect. According to the documentation of <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/documentation/#connect" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Kafka<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <em>Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems. It makes it simple to quickly define connectors that move large collections of data into and out of Kafka</em>. Kafka Connect supports two types of connectors - source and sink. Source connectors are used to ingest messages from external systems into Kafka topics while messages are ingested into external systems form Kafka topics with sink connectors. In this post, I will introduce available Kafka connectors mainly for AWS services integration. Also, developing and deploying some of them will be covered in later posts.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="22272" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Integrate Glue Schema Registry with Your Python Kafka App</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>As Kafka producer and consumer apps are decoupled, they operate on Kafka topics rather than communicating with each other directly. As described in the <a href="https://docs.confluent.io/platform/current/schema-registry/index.html#sr-overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Confluent document<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <em>Schema Registry</em> provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/glue/latest/dg/schema-registry.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Glue Schema Registry<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-streams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Kinesis Data Streams<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-analytics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Lambda<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. In this post, we will discuss how to integrate Python Kafka producer and consumer apps In AWS Lambda with the Glue Schema Registry.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/featured.png" length="46040" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 2 MSK and Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In Part 1, we discussed a streaming ingestion solution using <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eventbridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">EventBridge<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lambda<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/redshift-serverless/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redshift Serverless<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. Athena provides the <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/athena/latest/ug/connectors-msk.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK connector<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> to enable SQL queries on Apache Kafka topics directly, and it can also facilitate the extraction of insights without setting up an additional pipeline to store data into S3. In this post, we discuss how to update the streaming ingestion solution so that data in the Kafka topic can be queried by Athena instead of Redshift.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/featured.png" length="43403" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 1 MSK and Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://kafka.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Kafka<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform. Previously loading data from Kafka into Redshift and Athena usually required Kafka connectors (e.g. <a href="https://www.confluent.io/hub/confluentinc/kafka-connect-aws-redshift" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Redshift Sink Connector<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://www.confluent.io/hub/confluentinc/kafka-connect-s3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon S3 Sink Connector<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>). Recently these AWS services provide features to ingest data from Kafka directly, which facilitates a simpler architecture that achieves low-latency and high-speed ingestion of streaming data. In part 1 of the <em>simplify streaming ingestion on AWS</em> series, we discuss how to develop an end-to-end streaming ingestion solution using <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eventbridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">EventBridge<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lambda<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/redshift-serverless/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redshift Serverless<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> on AWS.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/featured.png" length="32864" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How to configure Kafka consumers to seek offsets by timestamp</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Normally we consume Kafka messages from the beginning/end of a topic or last committed offsets. For backfilling or troubleshooting, however, we need to consume messages from a certain timestamp occasionally. If we know which topic partition to choose e.g. by <a href="https://kafka-python.readthedocs.io/en/master/apidoc/KafkaConsumer.html#kafka.KafkaConsumer.assign" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">assigning a topic partition<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, we can easily override the fetch offset to a specific timestamp. When we deploy multiple consumer instances together, however, we make them <a href="https://kafka-python.readthedocs.io/en/master/apidoc/KafkaConsumer.html#kafka.KafkaConsumer.subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subscribe to a topic<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and topic partitions are dynamically assigned, which means we cannot determine which fetch offset to use for an instance. In this post, we develop Kafka producer and consumer applications using the <a href="https://kafka-python.readthedocs.io/en/master/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">kafka-python<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> package and discuss how to configure the consumer instances to seek offsets to a specific timestamp where topic partitions are dynamically assigned by subscription.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/featured.png" length="47217" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 2 MSK Deployment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In the <a href="/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1">previous post</a>, we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution with a schema registry. A local development environment is set up using Docker Compose. The Debezium and Confluent S3 connectors are deployed with the Confluent Avro converter and the Apicurio registry is used as the schema registry service. A quick example is shown to illustrate how schema evolution can be managed by the schema registry. In this post, we&rsquo;ll build the solution on AWS using <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/features/msk-connect/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSK Connect<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/Aurora.AuroraPostgreSQL.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aurora PostgreSQL<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/ecs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ECS<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>When we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution in <a href="/blog/2021-12-12-datalake-demo-part2">one of the earlier posts</a>, we used the JSON converter that comes with Kafka Connect. We optionally enabled the key and value schemas and the topic messages include those schemas together with payload. It seems to be convenient at first as the messages are saved into S3 on their own. However, it became cumbersome when we tried to use the <a href="https://hudi.apache.org/docs/hoodie_streaming_ingestion" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DeltaStreamer<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> utility. Specifically it requires the scheme of the files, but unfortunately we cannot use the schema that is generated by the default JSON converter - it returns the <a href="https://www.confluent.io/blog/kafka-connect-deep-dive-converters-serialization-explained/#json-schemas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">struct type<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, which is not supported by the Hudi utility. In order to handle this issue, we created a schema with the <a href="https://avro.apache.org/docs/current/spec.html#schema_record" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">record type<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> using the Confluent Avro converter and used it after saving on S3. However, as we aimed to manage a long-running process, generating a schema manually was not an optimal solution because, for example, we&rsquo;re not able to handle schema evolution effectively. In this post, we&rsquo;ll discuss an improved architecture that makes use of a schema registry that resides outside the Kafka cluster and allows the producers and consumers to reference the schemas externally.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>