<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>SSL/TLS on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/ssl/tls/</link><description>Recent content in SSL/TLS on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2025 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/ssl/tls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 9 SSL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to configure TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) encryption with Java and Python client examples. SSL encryption is a one-way verification process where a server certificate is verified by a client via SSL Handshake. To improve security, we can add client authentication either by enforcing two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers (SSL authentication). Or we can choose a separate authentication mechanism, which is typically Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/featured.png" length="471471" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 8 SSL Encryption</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</guid><description>By default, Apache Kafka communicates in PLAINTEXT, which means that all data is sent without being encrypted. To secure communication, we can configure Kafka clients and other components to use Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption. Note that TLS is also referred to Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) or TLS/SSL. SSL is the predecessor of TLS, and has been deprecated since June 2015. However, it is used in configuration and code instead of TLS for historical reasons.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/featured.png" length="469311" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>