<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Kafka Streams on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/kafka-streams/</link><description>Recent content in Kafka Streams on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2026 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/kafka-streams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Flink Table API - Declarative Analytics for Supplier Stats in Real Time</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-17-kotlin-getting-started-flink-table/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-17-kotlin-getting-started-flink-table/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In the last post, we explored the fine-grained control of Flink&rsquo;s DataStream API. Now, we&rsquo;ll approach the same problem from a higher level of abstraction using the <strong>Flink Table API</strong>. This post demonstrates how to build a declarative analytics pipeline that processes our continuous stream of Avro-formatted order events. We will define a <code>Table</code> on top of a <code>DataStream</code> and use SQL-like expressions to perform windowed aggregations. This example highlights the power and simplicity of the Table API for analytical tasks and showcases Flink&rsquo;s seamless integration between its different API layers to handle complex requirements like late data.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-17-kotlin-getting-started-flink-table/featured.png" length="144113" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Flink DataStream API - Scalable Event Processing for Supplier Stats</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-10-kotlin-getting-started-flink-datastream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-10-kotlin-getting-started-flink-datastream/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Building on our exploration of stream processing, we now transition from Kafka&rsquo;s native library to <strong>Apache Flink</strong>, a powerful, general-purpose distributed processing engine. In this post, we&rsquo;ll dive into Flink&rsquo;s foundational <strong>DataStream API</strong>. We will tackle the same supplier statistics problem - analyzing a stream of Avro-formatted order events - but this time using Flink&rsquo;s robust features for stateful computation. This example will highlight Flink&rsquo;s sophisticated event-time processing with watermarks and its elegant, built-in mechanisms for handling late-arriving data through side outputs.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-10-kotlin-getting-started-flink-datastream/featured.png" length="142918" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Streams - Lightweight Real-Time Processing for Supplier Stats</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-03-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-streams/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-03-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-streams/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this post, we shift our focus from basic Kafka clients to real-time stream processing with <strong>Kafka Streams</strong>. We&rsquo;ll explore a Kotlin application designed to analyze a continuous stream of Avro-formatted order events, calculate supplier statistics in tumbling windows, and intelligently handle late-arriving data. This example demonstrates the power of Kafka Streams for building lightweight, yet robust, stream processing applications directly within your Kafka ecosystem, leveraging event-time processing and custom logic.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-06-03-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-streams/featured.png" length="131804" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>