<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Engineering on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Remotely Using Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</guid><description>When we develop a Spark application on EMR, we can use docker for local development or notebooks via EMR Studio (or EMR Notebooks). However, the local development option is not viable if the size of data is large. Also, I am not a fan of notebooks as it is not possible to utilise the features my editor supports such as syntax highlighting, autocomplete and code formatting. Moreover, it is not possible to organise code into modules and to perform unit testing properly with that option.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/featured.png" length="72448" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Your Development on AWS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</guid><description>When I wrote my data lake demo series (part 1, part 2 and part 3) recently, I used an Aurora PostgreSQL, MSK and EMR cluster. All of them were deployed to private subnets and dedicated infrastructure was created using CloudFormation. Using the infrastructure as code (IaC) tool helped a lot, but it resulted in creating 7 CloudFormation stacks, which was a bit harder to manage in the end. Then I looked into how to simplify building infrastructure and managing resources on AWS and decided to use Terraform instead.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/featured.png" length="46253" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Yet another serverless solution for invoking AWS Lambda at a sub-minute frequency</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/</guid><description>Triggering a Lambda function by an EventBridge Events rule can be used as a _serverless _replacement of cron job. The highest frequency of it is one invocation per minute so that it cannot be used directly if you need to schedule a Lambda function more frequently. For example, it may be refreshing an application with real time metrics from an Amazon Connect instance where some metrics are updated every 15 seconds.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/featured.png" length="46921" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Adding Authorization to a Graphql API</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/</guid><description>Authorization is the mechanism that controls who can do what on which resource in an application. Although it is a critical part of an application, there are limited resources available on how to build authorization into an app effectively. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be illustrating how to set up authorization in a GraphQL API using a custom directive and Oso, an open-source authorization library. This tutorial covers the NodeJS variant of Oso, but it also supports Python and other languages.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/featured.png" length="52143" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Dynamic Routing and Centralized Auth with Traefik, Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</guid><description>Ingress in Kubernetes exposes HTTP and HTTPS routes from outside the cluster to services within the cluster. By setting rules, it routes requests to appropriate services (precisely requests are sent to individual Pods by Ingress Controller). Rules can be set up dynamically and I find it&amp;rsquo;s more efficient compared to traditional reverse proxy.
Traefik is a modern HTTP reverse proxy and load balancer and it can be used as a Kubernetes Ingress Controller.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/featured.png" length="139790" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Distributed Task Queue with Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</guid><description>While I&amp;rsquo;m looking into Apache Airflow, a workflow management tool, I thought it would be beneficial to get some understanding of how Celery works. To do so, I built a simple web service that sends tasks to Celery workers and collects the results from them. FastAPI is used for developing the web service and Redis is used for the message broker and result backend. During the development, I thought it would be possible to implement similar functionality in R with Rserve.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/featured.png" length="51615" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Linux Dev Environment on Windows</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</guid><description>I use Linux containers a lot for development. Having Windows computers at home and work, I used to use Linux VMs on VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad option but it requires a lot of resources. Recently, after my home computer was updated, I was not able to start my hypervisor anymore. Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t like huge resource consumption of it so that I began to look for a different development environment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/featured.png" length="187978" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Local Development with LocalStack</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</guid><description>LocalStack provides an easy-to-use test/mocking framework for developing AWS applications. In this post, a web service will be used for demonstrating how to utilize LocalStack for development.
Specifically a simple web service built with Flask-RestPlus is used. It supports simple CRUD operations against a database table. It is set that SQS and Lambda are used for creating and updating a record. When a POST or PUT request is made, the service sends a message to a SQS queue and directly returns 204 reponse.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/featured.png" length="164886" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Cronicle Multi Server Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/</guid><description>Accroding to the project GitHub repository,
Cronicle is a multi-server task scheduler and runner, with a web based front-end UI. It handles both scheduled, repeating and on-demand jobs, targeting any number of slave servers, with real-time stats and live log viewer.
By default, Cronicle is configured to launch a single master server - task scheduling is controlled by the master server. For high availability, it is important that another server takes the role of master when the existing master server fails.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/featured.png" length="64396" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>