<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Engineering on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Remotely Using Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
When we develop a Spark application on EMR, we can use docker for local development or notebooks via EMR Studio (or EMR Notebooks). However, the local development option is not viable if the size of data is large. Also, I am not a fan of notebooks as it is not possible to utilise the features my editor supports such as syntax highlighting, autocomplete and code formatting.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/featured.png" length="72448" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Your Development on AWS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
When I wrote my data lake demo series (part 1, part 2 and part 3) recently, I used an Aurora PostgreSQL, MSK and EMR cluster. All of them were deployed to private subnets and dedicated infrastructure was created using CloudFormation. Using the infrastructure as code (IaC) tool helped a lot, but it resulted in creating 7 CloudFormation stacks, which was a bit harder to manage in the end.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/featured.png" length="46253" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Yet another serverless solution for invoking AWS Lambda at a sub-minute frequency</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Triggering a Lambda function by an EventBridge Events rule can be used as a _serverless _replacement of cron job. The highest frequency of it is one invocation per minute so that it cannot be used directly if you need to schedule a Lambda function more frequently. For example, it may be refreshing an application with real time metrics from an Amazon Connect instance where some metrics are updated every 15 seconds.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/featured.png" length="46921" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Adding Authorization to a Graphql API</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Authorization is the mechanism that controls who can do what on which resource in an application. Although it is a critical part of an application, there are limited resources available on how to build authorization into an app effectively. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be illustrating how to set up authorization in a GraphQL API using a custom directive and Oso, an open-source authorization library.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/featured.png" length="52143" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Dynamic Routing and Centralized Auth with Traefik, Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</guid><description>Ingress in Kubernetes exposes HTTP and HTTPS routes from outside the cluster to services within the cluster. By setting rules, it routes requests to appropriate services (precisely requests are sent to individual Pods by Ingress Controller). Rules can be set up dynamically and I find it&amp;rsquo;s more efficient compared to traditional reverse proxy.
Traefik is a modern HTTP reverse proxy and load balancer and it can be used as a Kubernetes Ingress Controller.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/featured.png" length="139790" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Distributed Task Queue with Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</guid><description>While I&amp;rsquo;m looking into Apache Airflow, a workflow management tool, I thought it would be beneficial to get some understanding of how Celery works. To do so, I built a simple web service that sends tasks to Celery workers and collects the results from them. FastAPI is used for developing the web service and Redis is used for the message broker and result backend. During the development, I thought it would be possible to implement similar functionality in R with Rserve.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/featured.png" length="51615" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Linux Dev Environment on Windows</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</guid><description>I use Linux containers a lot for development. Having Windows computers at home and work, I used to use Linux VMs on VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad option but it requires a lot of resources. Recently, after my home computer was updated, I was not able to start my hypervisor anymore. Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t like huge resource consumption of it so that I began to look for a different development environment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/featured.png" length="187978" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Local Development with LocalStack</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</guid><description>LocalStack provides an easy-to-use test/mocking framework for developing AWS applications. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to utilize LocalStack for development using a web service.
Specifically a simple web service built with Flask-RestPlus is used. It supports simple CRUD operations against a database table. It is set that SQS and Lambda are used for creating and updating a record. When a POST or PUT request is made, the service sends a message to a SQS queue and directly returns 204 reponse.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/featured.png" length="164886" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Cronicle Multi Server Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/</guid><description>Accroding to the project GitHub repository,
Cronicle is a multi-server task scheduler and runner, with a web based front-end UI. It handles both scheduled, repeating and on-demand jobs, targeting any number of slave servers, with real-time stats and live log viewer.
By default, Cronicle is configured to launch a single master server - task scheduling is controlled by the master server. For high availability, it is important that another server takes the role of master when the existing master server fails.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/featured.png" length="64396" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Quick Test to Wrap Python in R</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</guid><description>As mentioned in an earlier post, things that are not easy in R can be relatively simple in other languages. Another example would be connecting to Amazon Web Services. In relation to s3, although there are a number of existing packages, many of them seem to be deprecated, premature or platform-dependent. (I consider the cloudyr project looks promising though.)
If there isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive R-way of doing something yet, it may be necessary to create it from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python for R Users</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</guid><description>There seem to be growing interest in Python in the R cummunity. While there can be a range of opinions about using R over Python (or vice versa) for exploratory data analysis, fitting statistical/machine learning algorithms and so on, I consider one of the strongest attractions of using Python comes from the fact that Python is a general purpose programming language. As more developers are involved in, it can provide a way to get jobs done easily, which can be tricky in R.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</guid><description>When I bagan to teach myself C# 3 years ago, I only had some experience in interactive analysis tools such as MATLAB and R - I didn&amp;rsquo;t consider R as a programming language at that time. The general purpose programming language shares some common features (data type, loop, if&amp;hellip;) but it is rather different in the way how code is written/organized, which is object oriented. Therefore, while it was not a problem to grap the common features, it took quite some time to understand and keep my code in an object oriented way.</description></item><item><title>Setup Random Seeds on Caret Package</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-05-30-setup-random-seeds-on-caret-package/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-05-30-setup-random-seeds-on-caret-package/</guid><description>A short while ago I had a chance to perform analysis using the caret package. One of the requirements is to run it parallelly and to work in both Windows and Linux. The requirement can be met by using the parallel and doParallel packages as the caret package trains a model using the foreach package if clusters are registered by the doParallel package - further details about how to implement parallel processing on a single machine can be found in earlier posts (Link 1, Link 2 and Link 3).</description></item><item><title>Packaging Analysis</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-24-packaging-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-24-packaging-analysis/</guid><description>When I imagine a workflow, it is performing the same or similar tasks regularly (daily or weekly) in an automated way. Although those tasks can be executed in a script or a *source()*d script, it may not be easy to maintain separate scripts while the size of tasks gets bigger or if they have to be executed in different machines. In academia, reproducible research shares similar ideas but the level of reproducibility introduced in Gandrud, 2013 may not suffice in a business environment as the focus is documenting in a reproducible way.</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-17-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-17-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-2/</guid><description>In the previous article, parallel processing on a single machine using the snow and parallel packages are introduced. The four functions are an extension of lapply() with an additional argument that specifies a cluster object. In spite of their effectiveness and ease of use, there may be cases where creating a function that can be sent into clusters is not easy or looping may be more natural. In this article, another way of implementing parallel processing on a single machine is introduced using the foreach and doParallel packages where clusters are created by the parallel package.</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part III</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-19-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-19-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-3/</guid><description>In the previous posts, two groups of ways to implement parallel processing on a single machine are introduced. The first group is provided by the snow or parallel package and the functions are an extension of lapply() (LINK). The second group is based on an extension of the for construct (foreach, %dopar% and %:%). The foreach construct is provided by the foreach package while clusters are made and registered by the parallel and doParallel packages respectively (LINK).</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-14-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-14-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-1/</guid><description>Lack of multi-threading and memory limitation are two outstanding weaknesses of base R. In fact, however, if the size of data is not so large that it can be read in RAM, the former would be relatively easily handled by parallel processing, provided that multiple processors are equipped. This article introduces to a way of implementing parallel processing on a single machine using the snow and parallel packages - the examples are largely based on McCallum and Weston (2012).</description></item><item><title>Quick Trial of Adding Column</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-01-14-quick-trial-of-adding-column/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-01-14-quick-trial-of-adding-column/</guid><description>This is a quick trial of adding overall and conditional (by user) average columns in a data frame. base,plyr,dplyr,data.table,dplyr + data.table packages are used. Personally I perfer dplyr + data.table - dplyr for comperhensive syntax and data.table for speed.
1## set up variables 2size &amp;lt;- 36000 3numUsers &amp;lt;- 4900 4# roughly each user has 7 sessions 5numSessions &amp;lt;- (numUsers / 7) - ((numUsers / 7) %% 1) 6 7## create data frame 8set.</description></item><item><title>Looping without for</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-17-looping-without-for/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-17-looping-without-for/</guid><description>Purely programming point of view, I consider for-loops would be better to be avoided in R as
the script can be more readable it is easier to handle errors Some articles on the web indicate that looping functions (or apply family of functions) don&amp;rsquo;t guarantee faster execution and sometimes even slower. Although, assuming that the experiments are correct, in my opinion, code readability itself is beneficial enough to avoid for-loops. Even worse, R&amp;rsquo;s dynamic typing system coupled with poor readability can result in a frustrating consequence as the code grows.</description></item><item><title>Short R Examples</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-03-short-r-examples/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-03-short-r-examples/</guid><description>As I don&amp;rsquo;t use R at work yet, I haven&amp;rsquo;t got enough chances to learn R by doing. Together with teaching myself machine learning with R, I consider it would be a good idea to collect examples on the web. Recently I have been visiting a Linkedin group called The R Project for Statistical Computing and suggesting scripts on data manipulation or programming topics. Actually I expected some of the topics may also be helpful to learn machine learning/statistics but, possibly due to lack of understaning of the topics in context, I&amp;rsquo;ve found only a few - it may be necessary to look for another source.</description></item><item><title>Summarise Stock Returns from Multiple Files</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-27-summarise-stock-returns-from-multiple-files/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-27-summarise-stock-returns-from-multiple-files/</guid><description><![CDATA[This post is a slight extension of the previous two articles (Download Stock Data - Part I, Download Stock Data - Part II) and we discuss how to produce gross returns, standard deviation and correlation of multiple shares.
The following packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(reshape2) 5library(plyr) 6library(dplyr) The script begins with creating a data folder in the format of data_YYYY-MM-DD.
1# create data folder 2dataDir &lt;- paste0(&#34;data&#34;,&#34;_&#34;,format(Sys.Date(),&#34;%Y-%m-%d&#34;)) 3if(file.exists(dataDir)) { 4 unlink(dataDir, recursive = TRUE) 5 dir.]]></description></item><item><title>Download Stock Data - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-21-download-stock-data-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-21-download-stock-data-2/</guid><description>In an earlier article, a way to download stock price data files from Google, save it into a local drive and merge them into a single data frame. If files are not large, however, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be effective and, in this article, files are downloaded and merged internally.
The following packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(plyr) 5library(dplyr) Taking urls as file locations, files are directly read using llply and they are combined using rbind_all.</description></item><item><title>Download Stock Data - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-20-download-stock-data-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-20-download-stock-data-1/</guid><description>This article illustrates how to download stock price data files from Google, save it into a local drive and merge them into a single data frame. This script is slightly modified from a script which downloads RStudio package download log data. The original source can be found here.
First of all, the following three packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(plyr) 5library(dplyr) The script begins with creating a folder to save data files.</description></item></channel></rss>