<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>SparkR on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/sparkr/</link><description>Recent content in SparkR on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2025 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/sparkr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Boost SparkR with Hive</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-04-30-boost-sparkr-with-hive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-04-30-boost-sparkr-with-hive/</guid><description>In the previous post, it is demonstrated how to start SparkR in local and cluster mode. While SparkR is in active development, it is yet to fully support Spark&amp;rsquo;s key libraries such as MLlib and Spark Streaming. Even, as a data processing engine, this R API is still limited as it is not possible to manipulate RDDs directly but only via Spark SQL/DataFrame API. As can be checked in the API doc, SparkR rebuilds many existing R functions to work with Spark DataFrame and notably it borrows some functions from the dplyr package.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start SparkR in Local and Cluster Mode</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-03-02-quick-start-sparkr-in-local-and-cluster-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-03-02-quick-start-sparkr-in-local-and-cluster-mode/</guid><description>In the previous post, a Spark cluster is set up using 2 VirtualBox Ubuntu guests. While this is a viable option for many, it is not always for others. For those who find setting-up such a cluster is not convenient, there&amp;rsquo;s still another option, which is relying on the local mode of Spark. In this post, a BitBucket repository is introduced, which is a R project that includes Spark 1.6.0 Pre-built for Hadoop 2.</description></item><item><title>Spark Cluster Setup on VirtualBox</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-02-22-spark-cluster-setup-on-virtualbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-02-22-spark-cluster-setup-on-virtualbox/</guid><description>We discuss how to set up a Spark cluser between 2 Ubuntu guests. Firstly it begins with machine preparation. Once a machine is baked, its image file (VDI) is be copied for the second one. Then how to launch a cluster by standalone mode is discussed. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Machine preparation If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, I recommend reading as it introduces Putty as well. Also, as Spark need Java Development Kit (JDK), you may need to apt-get it first - see this tutorial for further details.</description></item></channel></rss>