<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Kubernetes on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy Python Stream Processing App on Kubernetes - Part 2 Beam Pipeline on Flink Runner</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this post, we develop an <a href="https://beam.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Beam<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> pipeline using the <a href="https://beam.apache.org/documentation/sdks/python/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Python SDK<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> and deploy it on an <a href="https://flink.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> cluster via the <a href="https://beam.apache.org/documentation/runners/flink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Flink Runner<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. Same as <a href="/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1">Part I</a>, we deploy a Kafka cluster using the <a href="https://strimzi.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Strimzi Operator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> on a <a href="https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">minikube<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> cluster as the pipeline uses <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Kafka<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> topics for its data source and sink. Then, we develop the pipeline as a Python package and add the package to a custom Docker image so that Python user code can be executed externally. For deployment, we create a Flink session cluster via the <a href="https://nightlies.apache.org/flink/flink-kubernetes-operator-docs-main/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flink Kubernetes Operator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>, and deploy the pipeline using a Kubernetes job. Finally, we check the output of the application by sending messages to the input Kafka topic using a Python producer application.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/featured.png" length="58020" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Deploy Python Stream Processing App on Kubernetes - Part 1 PyFlink Application</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://nightlies.apache.org/flink/flink-kubernetes-operator-docs-main/docs/concepts/overview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flink Kubernetes Operator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> acts as a control plane to manage the complete deployment lifecycle of Apache Flink applications. With the operator, we can simplify deployment and management of Python stream processing applications. In this series, we discuss how to deploy a PyFlink application and Python Apache Beam pipeline on the <a href="https://beam.apache.org/documentation/runners/flink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flink Runner<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> on Kubernetes. In Part 1, we first deploy a Kafka cluster on a <a href="https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">minikube<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> cluster as the source and sink of the PyFlink application are Kafka topics. Then, the application source is packaged in a custom Docker image and deployed on the minikube cluster using the Flink Kubernetes Operator. Finally, the output of the application is checked by sending messages to the input Kafka topic using a Python producer application.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/featured.png" length="64457" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 3 Kafka Connect</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-11-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-11-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-3/</guid><description>Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems. It makes it simple to quickly define connectors that move large collections of data into and out of Kafka. In this post, we discuss how to set up a data ingestion pipeline using Kafka connectors. Fake customer and order data is ingested into Kafka topics using the MSK Data Generator. Also, we use the Confluent S3 sink connector to save the messages of the topics into a S3 bucket.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-11-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-3/featured.png" length="97270" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 2 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</guid><description>Apache Kafka has five core APIs, and we can develop applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster using the producer and consumer APIs. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java APIs, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, we discuss how to develop Kafka client applications using the kafka-python package on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Producer and Consumer (this post) Part 3 Kafka Connect Kafka Client Apps We create Kafka producer and consumer apps using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/featured.png" length="75889" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 1 Cluster Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is one of the key technologies for implementing data streaming architectures. Strimzi provides a way to run an Apache Kafka cluster and related resources on Kubernetes in various deployment configurations. In this series of posts, we will discuss how to create a Kafka cluster, to develop Kafka client applications in Python and to build a data pipeline using Kafka connectors on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup (this post) Part 2 Producer and Consumer Part 3 Kafka Connect Setup Kafka Cluster The Kafka cluster is deployed using the Strimzi Operator on a Minikube cluster.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/featured.png" length="108975" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How I Prepared for Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</guid><description>I recently obtained the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) certification. CKAD has been developed by The Linux Foundation and the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), to help expand the Kubernetes ecosystem through standardized training and certification. Specifically this certification is for Kubernetes engineers, cloud engineers and other IT professionals responsible for building, deploying, and configuring cloud native applications with Kubernetes. In this post, I will summarise how I prepared for the exam by reviewing three online courses and two practice tests that I went through.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/featured.png" length="5945" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Manage EMR on EKS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</guid><description>Amazon EMR on EKS is a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on EKS. While eksctl is popular for working with Amazon EKS clusters, it has limitations when it comes to building infrastructure that integrates multiple AWS services. Also, it is not straightforward to update EKS cluster resources incrementally with it. On the other hand Terraform can be an effective tool for managing infrastructure that includes not only EKS and EMR virtual clusters but also other AWS resources.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/featured.png" length="67936" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>EMR on EKS by Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</guid><description>EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on Amazon EKS. While a wide range of open source big data components are available in EMR on EC2, only Apache Spark is available in EMR on EKS. It is more flexible, however, that applications of different EMR versions can be run in multiple availability zones on either EC2 or Fargate.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/featured.png" length="76740" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Distributed Task Queue with Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</guid><description>While I&amp;rsquo;m looking into Apache Airflow, a workflow management tool, I thought it would be beneficial to get some understanding of how Celery works. To do so, I built a simple web service that sends tasks to Celery workers and collects the results from them. FastAPI is used for developing the web service and Redis is used for the message broker and result backend. During the development, I thought it would be possible to implement similar functionality in R with Rserve.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/featured.png" length="51615" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Linux Dev Environment on Windows</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</guid><description>I use Linux containers a lot for development. Having Windows computers at home and work, I used to use Linux VMs on VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad option but it requires a lot of resources. Recently, after my home computer was updated, I was not able to start my hypervisor anymore. Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t like huge resource consumption of it so that I began to look for a different development environment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/featured.png" length="187978" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>