<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Kubernetes on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Prepared for Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</guid><description>I recently obtained the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) certification. CKAD has been developed by The Linux Foundation and the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), to help expand the Kubernetes ecosystem through standardized training and certification. Specifically this certification is for Kubernetes engineers, cloud engineers and other IT professionals responsible for building, deploying, and configuring cloud native applications with Kubernetes. In this post, I will summarise how I prepared for the exam by reviewing three online courses and two practice tests that I went through.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/featured.png" length="5945" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Manage EMR on EKS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Amazon EMR on EKS is a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on EKS. While eksctl is popular for working with Amazon EKS clusters, it has limitations when it comes to building infrastructure that integrates multiple AWS services. Also, it is not straightforward to update EKS cluster resources incrementally with it.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/featured.png" length="67936" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>EMR on EKS by Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on Amazon EKS. While a wide range of open source big data components are available in EMR on EC2, only Apache Spark is available in EMR on EKS. It is more flexible, however, that applications of different EMR versions can be run in multiple availability zones on either EC2 or Fargate.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/featured.png" length="76740" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Distributed Task Queue with Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</guid><description>While I&amp;rsquo;m looking into Apache Airflow, a workflow management tool, I thought it would be beneficial to get some understanding of how Celery works. To do so, I built a simple web service that sends tasks to Celery workers and collects the results from them. FastAPI is used for developing the web service and Redis is used for the message broker and result backend. During the development, I thought it would be possible to implement similar functionality in R with Rserve.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/featured.png" length="51615" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Linux Dev Environment on Windows</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</guid><description>I use Linux containers a lot for development. Having Windows computers at home and work, I used to use Linux VMs on VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad option but it requires a lot of resources. Recently, after my home computer was updated, I was not able to start my hypervisor anymore. Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t like huge resource consumption of it so that I began to look for a different development environment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/featured.png" length="187978" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>