<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Glue Schema Registry on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/glue-schema-registry/</link><description>Recent content in Glue Schema Registry on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/glue-schema-registry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</guid><description>In Part 4, we developed Kafka producer and consumer applications using the kafka-python package. The Kafka messages are serialized as Json, but are not associated with a schema as there was not an integrated schema registry. Later we discussed how producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve in Part 5. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to enhance the existing applications by integrating AWS Glue Schema Registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/featured.png" length="57175" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 6 Kafka Connect with Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/</guid><description>In Part 3, we developed a data ingestion pipeline with fake online order data using Kafka Connect source and sink connectors. Schemas are not enabled on both of them as there was not an integrated schema registry. Later we discussed how producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve in Part 5. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to enhance the existing data ingestion pipeline by integrating AWS Glue Schema Registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/featured.png" length="60354" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 5 Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/</guid><description>As described in the Confluent document, Schema Registry provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the Glue Schema Registry supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and AWS Lambda.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/featured.png" length="51170" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>