<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Serverless on Jaehyeon</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/serverless/</link><description>Recent content in Serverless on Jaehyeon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API Development with R Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-19-api-development-with-r-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-19-api-development-with-r-2/</guid><description>In Part I, it is discussed how to serve an R function with plumber, Rserve and rApache. In this post, the APIs are deployed in a Docker container and, after showing example requests, their performance is compared. The rocker/r-ver:3.4 is used as the base image and each of the APIs is added to it. For simplicity, the APIs are served by Supervisor. For performance testing, Locust is used. The source of this post can be found in this GitHub repository.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-19-api-development-with-r-2/featured.png" length="367256" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>API Development with R Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-18-api-development-with-r-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-18-api-development-with-r-1/</guid><description>API is an effective way of distributing analysis outputs to external clients. When it comes to API development with R, however, there are not many choices. Probably development would be made with plumber, Rserve, rApache or OpenCPU if a client or bridge layer to R is not considered.
This is 2 part series in relation to API development with R. In this post, serving an R function with plumber, Rserve and rApache is discussed.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-18-api-development-with-r-1/featured.png" length="367256" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part IV - Serving R ML Model via S3</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</guid><description>In the previous posts, it is discussed how to package/deploy an R model with AWS Lambda and to expose the Lambda function via Amazon API Gateway. Main benefits of serverless architecture is cost-effectiveness and being hassle-free from provisioning/managing servers. While the API returns a predicted admission status value given GRE, GPA and Rank, there is an issue if it is served within a web application: Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS). This post discusses how to resolve this issue by updating API configuration and the Lambda function handler with a simple web application.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/featured.png" length="225463" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part III - Exposing R ML Model via APIG</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</guid><description>In Part I of this series, R and necessary libraries/packages together with a Lambda function handler are packaged and saved to Amazon S3. Then, in Part II, the package is deployed at AWS Lambda after creating and assigning a role to the Lambda function. Although the Lambda function can be called via the Invoke API, it&amp;rsquo;ll be much more useful if the function can be called as a web service (or API).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/featured.png" length="173293" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part II - Deploying R ML Model via Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</guid><description>In the previous post, serverless event-driven application development is introduced. Also how to package R, necessary libraries/packages and a Lambda function handler is discussed. No need of provisioning/managing servers is one of the key benefits of the architecture. It is also a cost-effective way of delivering a data product as functions are executed on-demand rather than in servers that run 24/7. Furthermore AWS Lambda free tier includes 1M free requests per month and 400,000 GB-seconds of compute time per month, which is available to both existing and new AWS customers indefinitely.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part I - Packaging R ML Model for Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[Let say you&rsquo;ve got a prediction model built in R and you&rsquo;d like to productionize it, for example, by serving it in a web application. One way is exposing the model through an API that returns the predicted result as a web service. However there are many issues. Firstly R is not a language for API development although there may be some ways - eg the plumber package. More importantly developing an API is not the end of the story as the API can&rsquo;t be served in a production system if it is not deployed/managed/upgraded/patched/&hellip; appropriately in a server or if it is not scalable, protected via authentication/authorization and so on.]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>