<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Apache Flink on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/apache-flink/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Flink on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/apache-flink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 2 Local Flink and MSK</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</guid><description>In this series of posts, we discuss a Flink (Pyflink) application that reads/writes from/to Kafka topics. In part 1, an app that targets a local Kafka cluster was created. In this post, we will update the app by connecting a Kafka cluster on Amazon MSK. The Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM and the app has additional jar dependency. As Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA) does not allow you to specify multiple pipeline jar files, we have to build a custom Uber Jar that combines multiple jar files.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="60947" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 1 Local Flink and Local Kafka</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Flink is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few. On AWS, we can deploy a Flink application via Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA), Amazon EMR and Amazon EKS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="55960" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>