<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Machine Learning on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup Random Seeds on Caret Package</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-05-30-setup-random-seeds-on-caret-package/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-05-30-setup-random-seeds-on-caret-package/</guid><description>A short while ago I had a chance to perform analysis using the caret package. One of the requirements is to run it parallelly and to work in both Windows and Linux. The requirement can be met by using the parallel and doParallel packages as the caret package trains a model using the foreach package if clusters are registered by the doParallel package - further details about how to implement parallel processing on a single machine can be found in earlier posts (Link 1, Link 2 and Link 3).</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part VI</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-07-tree-based-methods-6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-07-tree-based-methods-6/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III Part IV Part V Part VI (this post) A regression tree is evaluated using bagged trees in the previous article. In this article, the response variable of the same data set is converted into a binary factor variable and a classification tree is evaluated by comparing to bagged trees&amp;rsquo; individual oob/test errors, cumulative oob/test errors and variable importance measures.
Before getting started, note that the source of the classes can be found in this gist and, together with the relevant packages (see tags), it requires a utility function (bestParam()) that can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part V</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-05-tree-based-methods-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-05-tree-based-methods-5/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III Part IV Part V (this post) Part VI This article evaluates a single regression tree&amp;rsquo;s performance by comparing to bagged trees&amp;rsquo; individual oob/test errors, cumulative oob/test errors and variable importance measures.
Before getting started, note that the source of the classes can be found in this gist and, together with the relevant packages (see tags), it requires a utility function (bestParam()) that can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part IV</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-15-tree-based-methods-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-15-tree-based-methods-4/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III Part IV (this post) Part V Part VI While the last three articles illustrated the CART model for both classification (with equal/unequal costs) and regression tasks, this article is rather technical as it compares three packages: rpart, caret and mlr. For those who are not familiar with the last two packages, they are wrappers (or frameworks) that implement a range of models (or algorithms) in a unified way.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part III</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-14-tree-based-methods-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-14-tree-based-methods-3/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III (this post) Part IV Part V Part VI While classification tasks are implemented in the last two articles (Part I and Part II), a regression task is the topic of this article. While the caret package selects the tuning parameter (cp) that minimizes the error (RMSE), the rpart packages recommends the 1-SE rule, which selects the smallest tree within 1 standard error of the minimum cross validation error (xerror).</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-08-tree-based-methods-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-08-tree-based-methods-2/</guid><description>Part I Part II (this post) Part III Part IV Part V Part VI In the previous article (Tree Based Methods in R - Part I), a decision tree is created on the Carseats data which is in the chapter 8 lab of ISLR. In that article, potentially asymetric costs due to misclassification are not taken into account. When unbalance between false positive and false negative can have a significant impact, it can be explicitly adjusted either by altering prior (or empirical) probabilities or by adding a loss matrix.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-01-tree-based-methods-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-01-tree-based-methods-1/</guid><description>Part I (this post) Part II Part III Part IV Part V Part VI This is the first article about tree based methods using R. Carseats data in the chapter 8 lab of ISLR is used to perform classification analysis. Unlike the lab example, the rpart package is used to fit the CART model on the data and the caret package is used for tuning the pruning parameter (cp).</description></item></channel></rss>