<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Apache Kafka on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/apache-kafka/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Kafka on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/apache-kafka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 2 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</guid><description>Apache Kafka has five core APIs, and we can develop applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster using the producer and consumer APIs. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java APIs, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, we discuss how to develop Kafka client applications using the kafka-python package on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Producer and Consumer (this post) Part 3 Kafka Connect Kafka Client Apps We create Kafka producer and consumer apps using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/featured.png" length="75889" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 1 Cluster Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is one of the key technologies for implementing data streaming architectures. Strimzi provides a way to run an Apache Kafka cluster and related resources on Kubernetes in various deployment configurations. In this series of posts, we will discuss how to create a Kafka cluster, to develop Kafka client applications in Python and to build a data pipeline using Kafka connectors on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup (this post) Part 2 Producer and Consumer Part 3 Kafka Connect Setup Kafka Cluster The Kafka cluster is deployed using the Strimzi Operator on a Minikube cluster.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/featured.png" length="108975" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 5 Deploy Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to develop a data pipeline from Apache Kafka into OpenSearch locally using Docker. The pipeline will be deployed on AWS using Amazon MSK, Amazon MSK Connect and Amazon OpenSearch Service using Terraform in this post. First the infrastructure will be deployed that covers a Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Virtual Private Network (VPN) server, MSK Cluster and OpenSearch domain. Then Kafka source and sink connectors will be deployed on MSK Connect, followed by performing quick data analysis.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/featured.png" length="85575" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 4 Develop Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</guid><description>OpenSearch is a popular search and analytics engine and its use cases cover log analytics, real-time application monitoring, and clickstream analysis. OpenSearch can be deployed on its own or via Amazon OpenSearch Service. Apache Kafka is a distributed event store and stream-processing platform, and it aims to provide a unified, high-throughput, low-latency platform for handling real-time data feeds. On AWS, Apache Kafka can be deployed via Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/featured.png" length="61820" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 11 Kafka Authorization</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</guid><description>In the previous posts, we discussed how to implement client authentication by TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) and SASL authentication. One of the key benefits of client authentication is achieving user access control. Kafka ships with a pluggable, out-of-the box authorization framework, which is configured with the authorizer.class.name property in the server configuration and stores Access Control Lists (ACLs) in the cluster metadata (either Zookeeper or the KRaft metadata log). In this post, we will discuss how to configure Kafka authorization with Java and Python client examples while SASL is kept for client authentication.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/featured.png" length="458848" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 10 SASL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) authentication to improve security. It enforces two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers. Client authentication can also be enabled by Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL), and we will discuss how to implement SASL authentication with Java and Python client examples in this post.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Management App Part 3 Kafka Connect Part 4 Producer and Consumer Part 5 Glue Schema Registry Part 6 Kafka Connect with Glue Schema Registry Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry Part 8 SSL Encryption Part 9 SSL Authentication Part 10 SASL Authentication (this post) Part 11 Kafka Authorization Certificate Setup As we will leave Kafka communication to remain encrypted, we need to keep the components for SSL encryption.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/featured.png" length="471947" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 9 SSL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to configure TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) encryption with Java and Python client examples. SSL encryption is a one-way verification process where a server certificate is verified by a client via SSL Handshake. To improve security, we can add client authentication either by enforcing two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers (SSL authentication). Or we can choose a separate authentication mechanism, which is typically Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/featured.png" length="471471" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 3 Deploy Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</guid><description>As part of investigating how to utilize Kafka Connect effectively for AWS services integration, I demonstrated how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker in Part 2. Fake order data was generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector was configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table. In this post, I will illustrate how to deploy the data ingestion applications using Amazon MSK and MSK Connect.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="76240" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 8 SSL Encryption</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</guid><description>By default, Apache Kafka communicates in PLAINTEXT, which means that all data is sent without being encrypted. To secure communication, we can configure Kafka clients and other components to use Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption. Note that TLS is also referred to Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) or TLS/SSL. SSL is the predecessor of TLS, and has been deprecated since June 2015. However, it is used in configuration and code instead of TLS for historical reasons.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/featured.png" length="469311" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</guid><description>In Part 4, we developed Kafka producer and consumer applications using the kafka-python package. The Kafka messages are serialized as Json, but are not associated with a schema as there was not an integrated schema registry. Later we discussed how producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve in Part 5. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to enhance the existing applications by integrating AWS Glue Schema Registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/featured.png" length="57175" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 6 Kafka Connect with Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/</guid><description>In Part 3, we developed a data ingestion pipeline with fake online order data using Kafka Connect source and sink connectors. Schemas are not enabled on both of them as there was not an integrated schema registry. Later we discussed how producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve in Part 5. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to enhance the existing data ingestion pipeline by integrating AWS Glue Schema Registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/featured.png" length="60354" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 5 Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/</guid><description>As described in the Confluent document, Schema Registry provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the Glue Schema Registry supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and AWS Lambda.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/featured.png" length="51170" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 2 Develop Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we reviewed Kafka connectors focusing on AWS services integration. Among the available connectors, the suite of Apache Camel Kafka connectors and the Kinesis Kafka connector from the AWS Labs can be effective for building data ingestion pipelines on AWS. In this post, I will illustrate how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker. Fake order data will be generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector will be configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="87044" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 4 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed Kafka Connect to stream data to/from a Kafka cluster. Kafka also includes the Producer/Consumer APIs that allow client applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java clients, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to develop producer/consumer applications using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/featured.png" length="75255" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 3 Kafka Connect</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-25-kafka-development-with-docker-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-25-kafka-development-with-docker-part-3/</guid><description>According to the documentation of Apache Kafka, Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems. It makes it simple to quickly define connectors that move large collections of data into and out of Kafka. Kafka Connect supports two types of connectors - source and sink. Source connectors are used to ingest messages from external systems into Kafka topics while messages are ingested into external systems form Kafka topics with sink connectors.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-25-kafka-development-with-docker-part-3/featured.png" length="69998" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 2 Management App</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-18-kafka-development-with-docker-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-18-kafka-development-with-docker-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous post, I illustrated how to create a topic and to produce/consume messages using the command utilities provided by Apache Kafka. It is not convenient, however, for example, when you consume serialised messages where their schemas are stored in a schema registry. Also, the utilities don&amp;rsquo;t support to browse or manage related resources such as connectors and schemas. Therefore, a Kafka management app can be a good companion for development, which helps monitor and manage resources on an easy-to-use user interface.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-18-kafka-development-with-docker-part-2/featured.png" length="59675" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 1 Cluster Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m teaching myself modern data streaming architectures on AWS, and Apache Kafka is one of the key technologies, which can be used for messaging, activity tracking, stream processing and so on. While applications tend to be deployed to cloud, it can be much easier if we develop and test those with Docker and Docker Compose locally. As the series title indicates, I plan to publish articles that demonstrate Kafka and related tools in Dockerized environments.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/featured.png" length="98355" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 1 Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</guid><description>Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK) are two managed streaming services offered by AWS. Many resources on the web indicate Kinesis Data Streams is better when it comes to integrating with AWS services. However, it is not necessarily the case with the help of Kafka Connect. According to the documentation of Apache Kafka, Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="22272" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Integrate Glue Schema Registry with Your Python Kafka App</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</guid><description>As Kafka producer and consumer apps are decoupled, they operate on Kafka topics rather than communicating with each other directly. As described in the Confluent document, Schema Registry provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the Glue Schema Registry supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and AWS Lambda.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/featured.png" length="46040" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How to configure Kafka consumers to seek offsets by timestamp</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</guid><description>Normally we consume Kafka messages from the beginning/end of a topic or last committed offsets. For backfilling or troubleshooting, however, we need to consume messages from a certain timestamp occasionally. The Kafka consumer class of the kafka-python package has a method to seek a particular offset for a topic partition. Therefore, if we know which topic partition to choose e.g. by assigning a topic partition, we can easily override the fetch offset.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/featured.png" length="47217" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 2 MSK Deployment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution with a schema registry. A local development environment is set up using Docker Compose. The Debezium and Confluent S3 connectors are deployed with the Confluent Avro converter and the Apicurio registry is used as the schema registry service. A quick example is shown to illustrate how schema evolution can be managed by the schema registry. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll build the solution on AWS using MSK, MSK Connect, Aurora PostgreSQL and ECS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</guid><description>When we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution in one of the earlier posts, we used the JSON converter that comes with Kafka Connect. We optionally enabled the key and value schemas and the topic messages include those schemas together with payload. It seems to be convenient at first as the messages are saved into S3 on their own. However, it became cumbersome when we tried to use the DeltaStreamer utility.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>