<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Apache Kafka on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/apache-kafka/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Kafka on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/apache-kafka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 1 Kafka Cluster Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m teaching myself modern data streaming architectures on AWS, and Apache Kafka is one of the key technologies, which can be used for messaging, activity tracking, stream processing and so on. While applications tend to be deployed to cloud, it can be much easier if we develop and test those with Docker and Docker Compose locally. As the series title indicates, I plan to publish articles that demonstrate Kafka and related tools in Dockerized environments.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/featured.png" length="98355" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 2 MSK and Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
In Part 1, we discussed a streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless. Athena provides the MSK connector to enable SQL queries on Apache Kafka topics directly, and it can also facilitate the extraction of insights without setting up an additional pipeline to store data into S3. In this post, we discuss how to update the streaming ingestion solution so that data in the Kafka topic can be queried by Athena instead of Redshift.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/featured.png" length="43403" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 1 MSK and Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform. Previously loading data from Kafka into Redshift and Athena usually required Kafka connectors (e.g. Amazon Redshift Sink Connector and Amazon S3 Sink Connector). Recently these AWS services provide features to ingest data from Kafka directly, which facilitates a simpler architecture that achieves low-latency and high-speed ingestion of streaming data.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/featured.png" length="32864" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How to configure Kafka consumers to seek offsets by timestamp</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Normally we consume Kafka messages from the beginning/end of a topic or last committed offsets. For backfilling or troubleshooting, however, we need to consume messages from a certain timestamp occasionally. The Kafka consumer class of the kafka-python package has a method to seek a particular offset for a topic partition. Therefore, if we know which topic partition to choose e.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/featured.png" length="47217" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 2 MSK Deployment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
In the previous post, we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution with a schema registry. A local development environment is set up using Docker Compose. The Debezium and Confluent S3 connectors are deployed with the Confluent Avro converter and the Apicurio registry is used as the schema registry service. A quick example is shown to illustrate how schema evolution can be managed by the schema registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
When we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution in one of the earlier posts, we used the JSON converter that comes with Kafka Connect. We optionally enabled the key and value schemas and the topic messages include those schemas together with payload. It seems to be convenient at first as the messages are saved into S3 on their own.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>