<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Apache Airflow on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/apache-airflow/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Airflow on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/apache-airflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Revisit AWS Lambda Invoke Function Operator of Apache Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular workflow management platform. A wide range of AWS services are integrated with the platform by Amazon AWS Operators. AWS Lambda is one of the integrated services, and it can be used to develop workflows efficiently. The current Lambda Operator, however, just invokes a Lambda function, and it can fail to report the invocation result of a function correctly and to record the exact error message from failure.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="24814" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Thoughts on Apache Airflow AWS Lambda Operator</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular open-source workflow management platform. Typically tasks run remotely by Celery workers for scalability. In AWS, however, scalability can also be achieved using serverless computing services in a simpler way. For example, the ECS Operator allows to run dockerized tasks and, with the Fargate launch type, they can run in a serverless environment.
The ECS Operator alone is not sufficient because it can take up to several minutes to pull a Docker image and to set up network interface (for the case of Fargate launch type).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="44994" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>