<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Apache Airflow on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/apache-airflow/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Airflow on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2026 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/apache-airflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 6 ETL on Amazon Athena via Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-14-dbt-pizza-shop-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-14-dbt-pizza-shop-6/</guid><description>In Part 5, we developed a dbt project that that targets Apache Iceberg where transformations are performed on Amazon Athena. Two dimension tables that keep product and user records are created as Type 2 slowly changing dimension (SCD Type 2) tables, and one transactional fact table is built to keep pizza orders. To improve query performance, the fact table is denormalized to pre-join records from the dimension tables using the array and struct data types.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-14-dbt-pizza-shop-6/featured.png" length="82921" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 4 ETL on BigQuery via Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/</guid><description>In Part 3, we developed a dbt project that targets Google BigQuery with fictional pizza shop data. Two dimension tables that keep product and user records are created as Type 2 slowly changing dimension (SCD Type 2) tables, and one transactional fact table is built to keep pizza orders. The fact table is denormalized using nested and repeated fields for improving query performance. In this post, we discuss how to set up an ETL process on the project using Apache Airflow.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/featured.png" length="89588" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 2 ETL on PostgreSQL via Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-25-dbt-pizza-shop-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-25-dbt-pizza-shop-2/</guid><description>In this series of posts, we discuss data warehouse/lakehouse examples using data build tool (dbt) including ETL orchestration with Apache Airflow. In Part 1, we developed a dbt project on PostgreSQL with fictional pizza shop data. Two dimension tables that keep product and user records are created as Type 2 slowly changing dimension (SCD Type 2) tables, and one transactional fact table is built to keep pizza orders. In this post, we discuss how to set up an ETL process on the project using Apache Airflow.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-25-dbt-pizza-shop-2/featured.png" length="77355" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Revisit AWS Lambda Invoke Function Operator of Apache Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular workflow management platform. A wide range of AWS services are integrated with the platform by Amazon AWS Operators. AWS Lambda is one of the integrated services, and it can be used to develop workflows efficiently. The current Lambda Operator, however, just invokes a Lambda function, and it can fail to report the invocation result of a function correctly and to record the exact error message from failure.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="24814" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Thoughts on Apache Airflow AWS Lambda Operator</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular open-source workflow management platform. Typically tasks run remotely by Celery workers for scalability. In AWS, however, scalability can also be achieved using serverless computing services in a simpler way. For example, the ECS Operator allows to run dockerized tasks and, with the Fargate launch type, they can run in a serverless environment.
The ECS Operator alone is not sufficient because it can take up to several minutes to pull a Docker image and to set up network interface (for the case of Fargate launch type).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="44994" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>