<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>GCP on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/gcp/</link><description>Recent content in GCP on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2026 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Change Data Capture (CDC) Local Development with PostgreSQL, Debezium Server and Pub/Sub Emulator</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-11-07-cdc-local-dev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-11-07-cdc-local-dev/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><em>Change data capture</em> (CDC) is a data integration pattern to track changes in a database so that actions can be taken using the changed data. <a href="https://debezium.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Debezium</em><i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is probably the most popular open source platform for CDC. Originally providing Kafka source connectors, it also supports a ready-to-use application called <a href="https://debezium.io/documentation/reference/stable/operations/debezium-server.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Debezium server<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. The standalone application can be used to stream change events to other messaging infrastructure such as Google Cloud Pub/Sub, Amazon Kinesis and Apache Pulsar. In this post, we develop a CDC solution locally using Docker. The source of the <a href="https://console.cloud.google.com/marketplace/product/bigquery-public-data/thelook-ecommerce" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">theLook eCommerce<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> is modified to generate data continuously, and the data is inserted into multiple tables of a PostgreSQL database. Among those tables, two of them are tracked by the Debezium server, and it pushes row-level changes of those tables into Pub/Sub topics on the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/pubsub/docs/emulator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pub/Sub emulator<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a>. Finally, messages of the topics are read by a Python application.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-11-07-cdc-local-dev/featured.png" length="83605" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 4 ETL on BigQuery via Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/</guid><description>In Part 3, we developed a dbt project that targets Google BigQuery with fictional pizza shop data. Two dimension tables that keep product and user records are created as Type 2 slowly changing dimension (SCD Type 2) tables, and one transactional fact table is built to keep pizza orders. The fact table is denormalized using nested and repeated fields for improving query performance. In this post, we discuss how to set up an ETL process on the project using Apache Airflow.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/featured.png" length="89588" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 3 Modelling on BigQuery</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-08-dbt-pizza-shop-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-08-dbt-pizza-shop-3/</guid><description>In this series, we discuss practical examples of data warehouse and lakehouse development where data transformation is performed by the data build tool (dbt) and ETL is managed by Apache Airflow. In Part 1, we developed a dbt project on PostgreSQL using fictional pizza shop data. At the end, the data sets are modelled by two SCD type 2 dimension tables and one transactional fact table. In this post, we create a new dbt project that targets Google BigQuery.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-08-dbt-pizza-shop-3/featured.png" length="70297" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>