<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/series/kafka-connect-for-aws-services-integration/</link><description>Recent content in Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/series/kafka-connect-for-aws-services-integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 5 Deploy Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to develop a data pipeline from Apache Kafka into OpenSearch locally using Docker. The pipeline will be deployed on AWS using Amazon MSK, Amazon MSK Connect and Amazon OpenSearch Service using Terraform in this post. First the infrastructure will be deployed that covers a Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Virtual Private Network (VPN) server, MSK Cluster and OpenSearch domain. Then Kafka source and sink connectors will be deployed on MSK Connect, followed by performing quick data analysis.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/featured.png" length="85575" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 4 Develop Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</guid><description>OpenSearch is a popular search and analytics engine and its use cases cover log analytics, real-time application monitoring, and clickstream analysis. OpenSearch can be deployed on its own or via Amazon OpenSearch Service. Apache Kafka is a distributed event store and stream-processing platform, and it aims to provide a unified, high-throughput, low-latency platform for handling real-time data feeds. On AWS, Apache Kafka can be deployed via Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/featured.png" length="61820" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 3 Deploy Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
As part of investigating how to utilize Kafka Connect effectively for AWS services integration, I demonstrated how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker in Part 2. Fake order data was generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector was configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table. In this post, I will illustrate how to deploy the data ingestion applications using Amazon MSK and MSK Connect.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="76240" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 2 Develop Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
In Part 1, we reviewed Kafka connectors focusing on AWS services integration. Among the available connectors, the suite of Apache Camel Kafka connectors and the Kinesis Kafka connector from the AWS Labs can be effective for building data ingestion pipelines on AWS. In this post, I will illustrate how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker. Fake order data will be generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector will be configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="87044" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 1 Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK) are two managed streaming services offered by AWS. Many resources on the web indicate Kinesis Data Streams is better when it comes to integrating with AWS services. However, it is not necessarily the case with the help of Kafka Connect. According to the documentation of Apache Kafka, Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="22272" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>