<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Python on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 6 ETL on Amazon Athena via Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-14-dbt-pizza-shop-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-14-dbt-pizza-shop-6/</guid><description>In Part 5, we developed a dbt project that that targets Apache Iceberg where transformations are performed on Amazon Athena. Two dimension tables that keep product and user records are created as Type 2 slowly changing dimension (SCD Type 2) tables, and one transactional fact table is built to keep pizza orders. To improve query performance, the fact table is denormalized to pre-join records from the dimension tables using the array and struct data types.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-14-dbt-pizza-shop-6/featured.png" length="82921" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 5 Modelling on Amazon Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-07-dbt-pizza-shop-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-07-dbt-pizza-shop-5/</guid><description>In Part 1 and Part 3, we developed data build tool (dbt) projects that target PostgreSQL and BigQuery using fictional pizza shop data. The data is modelled by SCD type 2 dimension tables and one transactional fact table. While the order records should be joined with dimension tables to get complete details for PostgreSQL, the fact table is denormalized using nested and repeated fields to improve query performance for BigQuery.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-03-07-dbt-pizza-shop-5/featured.png" length="61499" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 4 ETL on BigQuery via Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/</guid><description>In Part 3, we developed a dbt project that targets Google BigQuery with fictional pizza shop data. Two dimension tables that keep product and user records are created as Type 2 slowly changing dimension (SCD Type 2) tables, and one transactional fact table is built to keep pizza orders. The fact table is denormalized using nested and repeated fields for improving query performance. In this post, we discuss how to set up an ETL process on the project using Apache Airflow.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-22-dbt-pizza-shop-4/featured.png" length="89588" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 3 Modelling on BigQuery</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-08-dbt-pizza-shop-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-08-dbt-pizza-shop-3/</guid><description>In this series, we discuss practical examples of data warehouse and lakehouse development where data transformation is performed by the data build tool (dbt) and ETL is managed by Apache Airflow. In Part 1, we developed a dbt project on PostgreSQL using fictional pizza shop data. At the end, the data sets are modelled by two SCD type 2 dimension tables and one transactional fact table. In this post, we create a new dbt project that targets Google BigQuery.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-02-08-dbt-pizza-shop-3/featured.png" length="70297" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 2 ETL on PostgreSQL via Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-25-dbt-pizza-shop-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-25-dbt-pizza-shop-2/</guid><description>In this series of posts, we discuss data warehouse/lakehouse examples using data build tool (dbt) including ETL orchestration with Apache Airflow. In Part 1, we developed a dbt project on PostgreSQL with fictional pizza shop data. Two dimension tables that keep product and user records are created as Type 2 slowly changing dimension (SCD Type 2) tables, and one transactional fact table is built to keep pizza orders. In this post, we discuss how to set up an ETL process on the project using Apache Airflow.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-25-dbt-pizza-shop-2/featured.png" length="77355" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) Pizza Shop Demo - Part 1 Modelling on PostgreSQL</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-18-dbt-pizza-shop-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-18-dbt-pizza-shop-1/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is a popular data transformation tool for data warehouse development. Moreover, it can be used for data lakehouse development thanks to open table formats such as Apache Iceberg, Apache Hudi and Delta Lake. dbt supports key AWS analytics services and I wrote a series of posts that discuss how to utilise dbt with Redshift, Glue, EMR on EC2, EMR on EKS, and Athena. Those posts focus on platform integration, however, they do not show realistic ETL scenarios.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-18-dbt-pizza-shop-1/featured.png" length="85093" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 2 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</guid><description>Apache Kafka has five core APIs, and we can develop applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster using the producer and consumer APIs. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java APIs, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, we discuss how to develop Kafka client applications using the kafka-python package on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Producer and Consumer (this post) Part 3 Kafka Connect Kafka Client Apps We create Kafka producer and consumer apps using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/featured.png" length="75889" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/</guid><description>Amazon MSK can be configured as an event source of a Lambda function. Lambda internally polls for new messages from the event source and then synchronously invokes the target Lambda function. With this feature, we can develop a Kafka consumer application in serverless environment where developers can focus on application logic. In this lab, we will discuss how to create a Kafka consumer using a Lambda function.
Introduction Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda (this post) Architecture Fake taxi ride data is sent to a Kafka topic by the Kafka producer application that is discussed in Lab 1.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/featured.png" length="138986" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Setup Local Development Environment for Apache Flink and Spark Using EMR Container Images</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-07-flink-spark-local-dev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-07-flink-spark-local-dev/</guid><description>Apache Flink became generally available for Amazon EMR on EKS from the EMR 6.15.0 releases, and we are able to pull the Flink (as well as Spark) container images from the ECR Public Gallery. As both of them can be integrated with the Glue Data Catalog, it can be particularly useful if we develop real time data ingestion/processing via Flink and build analytical queries using Spark (or any other tools or services that can access to the Glue Data Catalog).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-07-flink-spark-local-dev/featured.png" length="133053" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</guid><description>The value of data can be maximised when it is used without delay. With Apache Flink, we can build streaming analytics applications that incorporate the latest events with low latency. In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that writes accumulated taxi rides data into an OpenSearch cluster. It aggregates the number of trips/passengers and trip durations by vendor ID for a window of 5 seconds. The data is then used to create a chart that monitors the status of taxi rides in the OpenSearch Dashboard.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/featured.png" length="112340" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that exports Kafka topic messages into a S3 bucket. The app enriches the records by adding a new column using a user defined function and writes them via the FileSystem SQL connector. This allows us to achieve a simpler architecture compared to the original lab where the records are sent into Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose, enriched by a separate Lambda function and written to a S3 bucket afterwards.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/featured.png" length="160359" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that reads records from S3 and sends them into a Kafka topic. A custom pipeline Jar file will be created as the Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM, and it will be demonstrated how to execute the app in a Flink cluster deployed on Docker as well as locally as a typical Python app. We can assume the S3 data is static metadata that needs to be joined into another stream, and this exercise can be useful for data enrichment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/featured.png" length="139114" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Kafka producer application using AWS Lambda, which sends fake taxi ride data into a Kafka topic on Amazon MSK. A configurable number of the producer Lambda function will be invoked by an Amazon EventBridge schedule rule. In this way we are able to generate test data concurrently based on the desired volume of messages.
Introduction Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda (this post) Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda [Update 2023-11-06] Initially I planned to deploy Pyflink applications on Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink, but I changed the plan to use a local Flink cluster deployed on Docker.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/featured.png" length="138560" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Building Apache Flink Applications in Python</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/</guid><description>Building Apache Flink Applications in Java is a course to introduce Apache Flink through a series of hands-on exercises, and it is provided by Confluent. Utilising the Flink DataStream API, the course develops three Flink applications that populate multiple source data sets, collect them into a standardised data set, and aggregate it to produce usage statistics. As part of learning the Flink DataStream API in Pyflink, I converted the Java apps into Python equivalent while performing the course exercises in Pyflink.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/featured.png" length="154736" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</guid><description>Real Time Streaming with Amazon Kinesis is an AWS workshop that helps users build a streaming analytics application on AWS. Incoming events are stored in a number of streams of the Amazon Kinesis Data Streams service, and various other AWS services and tools are used to process and analyse data.
Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform, and it stores incoming events in topics. As part of learning real time streaming analytics on AWS, we can rebuild the analytics applications by replacing the Kinesis streams with Kafka topics.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/featured.png" length="138141" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 2 Deployment via AWS Managed Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</guid><description>This series aims to help those who are new to Apache Flink and Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink by re-implementing a simple fraud detection application that is discussed in an AWS workshop titled AWS Kafka and DynamoDB for real time fraud detection. In part 1, I demonstrated how to develop the application locally, and the app will be deployed via Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink in this post.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/featured.png" length="66221" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 3 AWS Managed Flink and MSK</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/</guid><description>In this series of posts, we discuss a Flink (Pyflink) application that reads/writes from/to Kafka topics. In the previous posts, I demonstrated a Pyflink app that targets a local Kafka cluster as well as a Kafka cluster on Amazon MSK. The app was executed in a virtual environment as well as in a local Flink cluster for improved monitoring. In this post, the app will be deployed via Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink, which is the easiest option to run Flink applications on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="74618" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 2 Local Flink and MSK</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</guid><description>In this series of posts, we discuss a Flink (Pyflink) application that reads/writes from/to Kafka topics. In part 1, an app that targets a local Kafka cluster was created. In this post, we will update the app by connecting a Kafka cluster on Amazon MSK. The Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM and the app has additional jar dependency. As Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink does not allow you to specify multiple pipeline jar files, we have to build a custom Uber Jar that combines multiple jar files.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="64005" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 1 Local Flink and Local Kafka</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Flink is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few. On AWS, we can deploy a Flink application via Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA), Amazon EMR and Amazon EKS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="55960" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Flink is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few. On AWS, we can deploy a Flink application via Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA), Amazon EMR and Amazon EKS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/featured.png" length="72929" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 11 Kafka Authorization</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</guid><description>In the previous posts, we discussed how to implement client authentication by TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) and SASL authentication. One of the key benefits of client authentication is achieving user access control. Kafka ships with a pluggable, out-of-the box authorization framework, which is configured with the authorizer.class.name property in the server configuration and stores Access Control Lists (ACLs) in the cluster metadata (either Zookeeper or the KRaft metadata log). In this post, we will discuss how to configure Kafka authorization with Java and Python client examples while SASL is kept for client authentication.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/featured.png" length="458848" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 10 SASL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) authentication to improve security. It enforces two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers. Client authentication can also be enabled by Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL), and we will discuss how to implement SASL authentication with Java and Python client examples in this post.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Management App Part 3 Kafka Connect Part 4 Producer and Consumer Part 5 Glue Schema Registry Part 6 Kafka Connect with Glue Schema Registry Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry Part 8 SSL Encryption Part 9 SSL Authentication Part 10 SASL Authentication (this post) Part 11 Kafka Authorization Certificate Setup As we will leave Kafka communication to remain encrypted, we need to keep the components for SSL encryption.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/featured.png" length="471947" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 9 SSL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to configure TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) encryption with Java and Python client examples. SSL encryption is a one-way verification process where a server certificate is verified by a client via SSL Handshake. To improve security, we can add client authentication either by enforcing two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers (SSL authentication). Or we can choose a separate authentication mechanism, which is typically Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/featured.png" length="471471" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 8 SSL Encryption</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</guid><description>By default, Apache Kafka communicates in PLAINTEXT, which means that all data is sent without being encrypted. To secure communication, we can configure Kafka clients and other components to use Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption. Note that TLS is also referred to Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) or TLS/SSL. SSL is the predecessor of TLS, and has been deprecated since June 2015. However, it is used in configuration and code instead of TLS for historical reasons.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/featured.png" length="469311" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</guid><description>In Part 4, we developed Kafka producer and consumer applications using the kafka-python package. The Kafka messages are serialized as Json, but are not associated with a schema as there was not an integrated schema registry. Later we discussed how producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve in Part 5. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to enhance the existing applications by integrating AWS Glue Schema Registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/featured.png" length="57175" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 4 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed Kafka Connect to stream data to/from a Kafka cluster. Kafka also includes the Producer/Consumer APIs that allow client applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java clients, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to develop producer/consumer applications using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/featured.png" length="75255" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Integrate Glue Schema Registry with Your Python Kafka App</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</guid><description>As Kafka producer and consumer apps are decoupled, they operate on Kafka topics rather than communicating with each other directly. As described in the Confluent document, Schema Registry provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the Glue Schema Registry supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and AWS Lambda.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/featured.png" length="46040" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 2 MSK and Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</guid><description>In Part 1, we discussed a streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless. Athena provides the MSK connector to enable SQL queries on Apache Kafka topics directly, and it can also facilitate the extraction of insights without setting up an additional pipeline to store data into S3. In this post, we discuss how to update the streaming ingestion solution so that data in the Kafka topic can be queried by Athena instead of Redshift.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/featured.png" length="43403" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 1 MSK and Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform. Previously loading data from Kafka into Redshift and Athena usually required Kafka connectors (e.g. Amazon Redshift Sink Connector and Amazon S3 Sink Connector). Recently these AWS services provide features to ingest data from Kafka directly, which facilitates a simpler architecture that achieves low-latency and high-speed ingestion of streaming data. In part 1 of the simplify streaming ingestion on AWS series, we discuss how to develop an end-to-end streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/featured.png" length="32864" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How to configure Kafka consumers to seek offsets by timestamp</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</guid><description>Normally we consume Kafka messages from the beginning/end of a topic or last committed offsets. For backfilling or troubleshooting, however, we need to consume messages from a certain timestamp occasionally. If we know which topic partition to choose e.g. by assigning a topic partition, we can easily override the fetch offset to a specific timestamp. When we deploy multiple consumer instances together, however, we make them subscribe to a topic and topic partitions are dynamically assigned, which means we cannot determine which fetch offset to use for an instance.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/featured.png" length="47217" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Revisit AWS Lambda Invoke Function Operator of Apache Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular workflow management platform. A wide range of AWS services are integrated with the platform by Amazon AWS Operators. AWS Lambda is one of the integrated services, and it can be used to develop workflows efficiently. The current Lambda Operator, however, just invokes a Lambda function, and it can fail to report the invocation result of a function correctly and to record the exact error message from failure.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="24814" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Local Development of AWS Glue 3.0 and Later</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</guid><description>In an earlier post, I demonstrated how to set up a local development environment for AWS Glue 1.0 and 2.0 using a docker image that is published by the AWS Glue team and the Visual Studio Code Remote – Containers extension. Recently AWS Glue 3.0 was released, but a docker image for this version is not published. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate how to create a development environment for AWS Glue 3.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/featured.png" length="30923" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Glue Local Development with Docker and Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</guid><description>As described in the product page, AWS Glue is a serverless data integration service that makes it easy to discover, prepare, and combine data for analytics, machine learning, and application development. For development, a development endpoint is recommended, but it can be costly, inconvenient or unavailable (for Glue 2.0). The AWS Glue team published a Docker image that includes the AWS Glue binaries and all the dependencies packaged together. After inspecting it, I find some modifications are necessary in order to build a development environment on it.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/featured.png" length="19535" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Thoughts on Apache Airflow AWS Lambda Operator</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular open-source workflow management platform. Typically tasks run remotely by Celery workers for scalability. In AWS, however, scalability can also be achieved using serverless computing services in a simpler way. For example, the ECS Operator allows to run dockerized tasks and, with the Fargate launch type, they can run in a serverless environment.
The ECS Operator alone is not sufficient because it can take up to several minutes to pull a Docker image and to set up network interface (for the case of Fargate launch type).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="44994" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Dynamic Routing and Centralized Auth with Traefik, Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</guid><description>Ingress in Kubernetes exposes HTTP and HTTPS routes from outside the cluster to services within the cluster. By setting rules, it routes requests to appropriate services (precisely requests are sent to individual Pods by Ingress Controller). Rules can be set up dynamically and I find it&amp;rsquo;s more efficient compared to traditional reverse proxy.
Traefik is a modern HTTP reverse proxy and load balancer and it can be used as a Kubernetes Ingress Controller.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/featured.png" length="139790" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Distributed Task Queue with Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</guid><description>While I&amp;rsquo;m looking into Apache Airflow, a workflow management tool, I thought it would be beneficial to get some understanding of how Celery works. To do so, I built a simple web service that sends tasks to Celery workers and collects the results from them. FastAPI is used for developing the web service and Redis is used for the message broker and result backend. During the development, I thought it would be possible to implement similar functionality in R with Rserve.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/featured.png" length="51615" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Linux Dev Environment on Windows</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</guid><description>I use Linux containers a lot for development. Having Windows computers at home and work, I used to use Linux VMs on VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad option but it requires a lot of resources. Recently, after my home computer was updated, I was not able to start my hypervisor anymore. Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t like huge resource consumption of it so that I began to look for a different development environment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/featured.png" length="187978" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Local Development with LocalStack</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</guid><description>LocalStack provides an easy-to-use test/mocking framework for developing AWS applications. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to utilize LocalStack for development using a web service.
Specifically a simple web service built with Flask-RestPlus is used. It supports simple CRUD operations against a database table. It is set that SQS and Lambda are used for creating and updating a record. When a POST or PUT request is made, the service sends a message to a SQS queue and directly returns 204 reponse.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/featured.png" length="164886" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part IV - Serving R ML Model via S3</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</guid><description>In the previous posts, it is discussed how to package/deploy an R model with AWS Lambda and to expose the Lambda function via Amazon API Gateway. Main benefits of serverless architecture is cost-effectiveness and being hassle-free from provisioning/managing servers. While the API returns a predicted admission status value given GRE, GPA and Rank, there is an issue if it is served within a web application: Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS). This post discusses how to resolve this issue by updating API configuration and the Lambda function handler with a simple web application.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/featured.png" length="225463" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part III - Exposing R ML Model via APIG</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</guid><description>In Part I of this series, R and necessary libraries/packages together with a Lambda function handler are packaged and saved to Amazon S3. Then, in Part II, the package is deployed at AWS Lambda after creating and assigning a role to the Lambda function. Although the Lambda function can be called via the Invoke API, it&amp;rsquo;ll be much more useful if the function can be called as a web service (or API).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/featured.png" length="173293" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part II - Deploying R ML Model via Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</guid><description>In the previous post, serverless event-driven application development is introduced. Also how to package R, necessary libraries/packages and a Lambda function handler is discussed. No need of provisioning/managing servers is one of the key benefits of the architecture. It is also a cost-effective way of delivering a data product as functions are executed on-demand rather than in servers that run 24/7. Furthermore AWS Lambda free tier includes 1M free requests per month and 400,000 GB-seconds of compute time per month, which is available to both existing and new AWS customers indefinitely.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part I - Packaging R ML Model for Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[Let say you&rsquo;ve got a prediction model built in R and you&rsquo;d like to productionize it, for example, by serving it in a web application. One way is exposing the model through an API that returns the predicted result as a web service. However there are many issues. Firstly R is not a language for API development although there may be some ways - eg the plumber package. More importantly developing an API is not the end of the story as the API can&rsquo;t be served in a production system if it is not deployed/managed/upgraded/patched/&hellip; appropriately in a server or if it is not scalable, protected via authentication/authorization and so on.]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Quick Test to Wrap Python in R</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</guid><description>As mentioned in an earlier post, things that are not easy in R can be relatively simple in other languages. Another example would be connecting to Amazon Web Services. In relation to s3, although there are a number of existing packages, many of them seem to be deprecated, premature or platform-dependent. (I consider the cloudyr project looks promising though.)
If there isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive R-way of doing something yet, it may be necessary to create it from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python for R Users</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</guid><description>There seem to be growing interest in Python in the R cummunity. While there can be a range of opinions about using R over Python (or vice versa) for exploratory data analysis, fitting statistical/machine learning algorithms and so on, I consider one of the strongest attractions of using Python comes from the fact that Python is a general purpose programming language. As more developers are involved in, it can provide a way to get jobs done easily, which can be tricky in R.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</guid><description>When I bagan to teach myself C# 3 years ago, I only had some experience in interactive analysis tools such as MATLAB and R - I didn&amp;rsquo;t consider R as a programming language at that time. The general purpose programming language shares some common features (data type, loop, if&amp;hellip;) but it is rather different in the way how code is written/organized, which is object oriented. Therefore, while it was not a problem to grap the common features, it took quite some time to understand and keep my code in an object oriented way.</description></item></channel></rss>