<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Blogs on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 2 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</guid><description>Apache Kafka has five core APIs, and we can develop applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster using the producer and consumer APIs. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java APIs, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, we discuss how to develop Kafka client applications using the kafka-python package on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Producer and Consumer (this post) Part 3 Kafka Connect Kafka Client Apps We create Kafka producer and consumer apps using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/featured.png" length="75889" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 1 Cluster Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is one of the key technologies for implementing data streaming architectures. Strimzi provides a way to run an Apache Kafka cluster and related resources on Kubernetes in various deployment configurations. In this series of posts, we will discuss how to create a Kafka cluster, to develop Kafka client applications in Python and to build a data pipeline using Kafka connectors on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup (this post) Part 2 Producer and Consumer Part 3 Kafka Connect Setup Kafka Cluster The Kafka cluster is deployed using the Strimzi Operator on a Minikube cluster.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/featured.png" length="108975" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/</guid><description>Amazon MSK can be configured as an event source of a Lambda function. Lambda internally polls for new messages from the event source and then synchronously invokes the target Lambda function. With this feature, we can develop a Kafka consumer application in serverless environment where developers can focus on application logic. In this lab, we will discuss how to create a Kafka consumer using a Lambda function.
Introduction Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda (this post) Architecture Fake taxi ride data is sent to a Kafka topic by the Kafka producer application that is discussed in Lab 1.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-14-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-7/featured.png" length="138986" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Setup Local Development Environment for Apache Flink and Spark Using EMR Container Images</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-07-flink-spark-local-dev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-07-flink-spark-local-dev/</guid><description>Apache Flink became generally available for Amazon EMR on EKS from the EMR 6.15.0 releases, and we are able to pull the Flink (as well as Spark) container images from the ECR Public Gallery. As both of them can be integrated with the Glue Data Catalog, it can be particularly useful if we develop real time data ingestion/processing via Flink and build analytical queries using Spark (or any other tools or services that can access to the Glue Data Catalog).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-07-flink-spark-local-dev/featured.png" length="133053" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-30-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-30-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-6/</guid><description>Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems. It makes it simple to quickly define connectors that move large collections of data into and out of Kafka. In this lab, we will discuss how to create a data pipeline that ingests data from a Kafka topic into a DynamoDB table using the Camel DynamoDB sink connector.
Introduction Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect (this post) Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda Architecture Fake taxi ride data is sent to a Kafka topic by the Kafka producer application that is discussed in Lab 1.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-30-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-6/featured.png" length="113252" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</guid><description>The value of data can be maximised when it is used without delay. With Apache Flink, we can build streaming analytics applications that incorporate the latest events with low latency. In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that writes accumulated taxi rides data into an OpenSearch cluster. It aggregates the number of trips/passengers and trip durations by vendor ID for a window of 5 seconds. The data is then used to create a chart that monitors the status of taxi rides in the OpenSearch Dashboard.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/featured.png" length="112340" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that exports Kafka topic messages into a S3 bucket. The app enriches the records by adding a new column using a user defined function and writes them via the FileSystem SQL connector. This allows us to achieve a simpler architecture compared to the original lab where the records are sent into Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose, enriched by a separate Lambda function and written to a S3 bucket afterwards.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-16-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-4/featured.png" length="160359" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that reads records from S3 and sends them into a Kafka topic. A custom pipeline Jar file will be created as the Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM, and it will be demonstrated how to execute the app in a Flink cluster deployed on Docker as well as locally as a typical Python app. We can assume the S3 data is static metadata that needs to be joined into another stream, and this exercise can be useful for data enrichment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/featured.png" length="139114" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Benefits and Opportunities of Stateful Stream Processing</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-02-stateful-stream-processing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-02-stateful-stream-processing/</guid><description>Stream processing technology is becoming more and more popular with companies big and small because it provides superior solutions for many established use cases such as data analytics, ETL, and transactional applications, but also facilitates novel applications, software architectures, and business opportunities. Beginning with traditional data infrastructures and application/data development patterns, this post introduces stateful stream processing and demonstrates to what extent it can improve the traditional development patterns. A consulting company can partner with her clients on their journeys of adopting stateful stream processing, and it can bring huge opportunities.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-02-stateful-stream-processing/featured.png" length="244920" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 5 Deploy Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to develop a data pipeline from Apache Kafka into OpenSearch locally using Docker. The pipeline will be deployed on AWS using Amazon MSK, Amazon MSK Connect and Amazon OpenSearch Service using Terraform in this post. First the infrastructure will be deployed that covers a Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Virtual Private Network (VPN) server, MSK Cluster and OpenSearch domain. Then Kafka source and sink connectors will be deployed on MSK Connect, followed by performing quick data analysis.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/featured.png" length="85575" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Kafka producer application using AWS Lambda, which sends fake taxi ride data into a Kafka topic on Amazon MSK. A configurable number of the producer Lambda function will be invoked by an Amazon EventBridge schedule rule. In this way we are able to generate test data concurrently based on the desired volume of messages.
Introduction Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda (this post) Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda [Update 2023-11-06] Initially I planned to deploy Pyflink applications on Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink, but I changed the plan to use a local Flink cluster deployed on Docker.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/featured.png" length="138560" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 4 Develop Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</guid><description>OpenSearch is a popular search and analytics engine and its use cases cover log analytics, real-time application monitoring, and clickstream analysis. OpenSearch can be deployed on its own or via Amazon OpenSearch Service. Apache Kafka is a distributed event store and stream-processing platform, and it aims to provide a unified, high-throughput, low-latency platform for handling real-time data feeds. On AWS, Apache Kafka can be deployed via Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/featured.png" length="61820" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Building Apache Flink Applications in Python</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/</guid><description>Building Apache Flink Applications in Java is a course to introduce Apache Flink through a series of hands-on exercises, and it is provided by Confluent. Utilising the Flink DataStream API, the course develops three Flink applications that populate multiple source data sets, collect them into a standardised data set, and aggregate it to produce usage statistics. As part of learning the Flink DataStream API in Pyflink, I converted the Java apps into Python equivalent while performing the course exercises in Pyflink.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-19-build-pyflink-apps/featured.png" length="154736" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How I Prepared for Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</guid><description>I recently obtained the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) certification. CKAD has been developed by The Linux Foundation and the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), to help expand the Kubernetes ecosystem through standardized training and certification. Specifically this certification is for Kubernetes engineers, cloud engineers and other IT professionals responsible for building, deploying, and configuring cloud native applications with Kubernetes. In this post, I will summarise how I prepared for the exam by reviewing three online courses and two practice tests that I went through.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/featured.png" length="5945" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</guid><description>Real Time Streaming with Amazon Kinesis is an AWS workshop that helps users build a streaming analytics application on AWS. Incoming events are stored in a number of streams of the Amazon Kinesis Data Streams service, and various other AWS services and tools are used to process and analyse data.
Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform, and it stores incoming events in topics. As part of learning real time streaming analytics on AWS, we can rebuild the analytics applications by replacing the Kinesis streams with Kafka topics.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/featured.png" length="138141" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 2 Deployment via AWS Managed Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</guid><description>This series aims to help those who are new to Apache Flink and Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink by re-implementing a simple fraud detection application that is discussed in an AWS workshop titled AWS Kafka and DynamoDB for real time fraud detection. In part 1, I demonstrated how to develop the application locally, and the app will be deployed via Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink in this post.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/featured.png" length="66221" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 3 AWS Managed Flink and MSK</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/</guid><description>In this series of posts, we discuss a Flink (Pyflink) application that reads/writes from/to Kafka topics. In the previous posts, I demonstrated a Pyflink app that targets a local Kafka cluster as well as a Kafka cluster on Amazon MSK. The app was executed in a virtual environment as well as in a local Flink cluster for improved monitoring. In this post, the app will be deployed via Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink, which is the easiest option to run Flink applications on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-04-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="74618" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 2 Local Flink and MSK</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/</guid><description>In this series of posts, we discuss a Flink (Pyflink) application that reads/writes from/to Kafka topics. In part 1, an app that targets a local Kafka cluster was created. In this post, we will update the app by connecting a Kafka cluster on Amazon MSK. The Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM and the app has additional jar dependency. As Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink does not allow you to specify multiple pipeline jar files, we have to build a custom Uber Jar that combines multiple jar files.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-28-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="64005" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Getting Started with Pyflink on AWS - Part 1 Local Flink and Local Kafka</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Flink is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few. On AWS, we can deploy a Flink application via Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA), Amazon EMR and Amazon EKS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-17-getting-started-with-pyflink-on-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="55960" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Flink is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few. On AWS, we can deploy a Flink application via Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics (KDA), Amazon EMR and Amazon EKS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/featured.png" length="72929" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 11 Kafka Authorization</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/</guid><description>In the previous posts, we discussed how to implement client authentication by TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) and SASL authentication. One of the key benefits of client authentication is achieving user access control. Kafka ships with a pluggable, out-of-the box authorization framework, which is configured with the authorizer.class.name property in the server configuration and stores Access Control Lists (ACLs) in the cluster metadata (either Zookeeper or the KRaft metadata log). In this post, we will discuss how to configure Kafka authorization with Java and Python client examples while SASL is kept for client authentication.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-20-kafka-development-with-docker-part-11/featured.png" length="458848" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 10 SASL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) authentication to improve security. It enforces two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers. Client authentication can also be enabled by Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL), and we will discuss how to implement SASL authentication with Java and Python client examples in this post.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Management App Part 3 Kafka Connect Part 4 Producer and Consumer Part 5 Glue Schema Registry Part 6 Kafka Connect with Glue Schema Registry Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry Part 8 SSL Encryption Part 9 SSL Authentication Part 10 SASL Authentication (this post) Part 11 Kafka Authorization Certificate Setup As we will leave Kafka communication to remain encrypted, we need to keep the components for SSL encryption.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-13-kafka-development-with-docker-part-10/featured.png" length="471947" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 9 SSL Authentication</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to configure TLS (SSL or TLS/SSL) encryption with Java and Python client examples. SSL encryption is a one-way verification process where a server certificate is verified by a client via SSL Handshake. To improve security, we can add client authentication either by enforcing two-way verification where a client certificate is verified by Kafka brokers (SSL authentication). Or we can choose a separate authentication mechanism, which is typically Simple Authentication and Security Layer (SASL).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-06-kafka-development-with-docker-part-9/featured.png" length="471471" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 3 Deploy Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</guid><description>As part of investigating how to utilize Kafka Connect effectively for AWS services integration, I demonstrated how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker in Part 2. Fake order data was generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector was configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table. In this post, I will illustrate how to deploy the data ingestion applications using Amazon MSK and MSK Connect.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="76240" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 8 SSL Encryption</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/</guid><description>By default, Apache Kafka communicates in PLAINTEXT, which means that all data is sent without being encrypted. To secure communication, we can configure Kafka clients and other components to use Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption. Note that TLS is also referred to Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) or TLS/SSL. SSL is the predecessor of TLS, and has been deprecated since June 2015. However, it is used in configuration and code instead of TLS for historical reasons.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-29-kafka-development-with-docker-part-8/featured.png" length="469311" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 7 Producer and Consumer with Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/</guid><description>In Part 4, we developed Kafka producer and consumer applications using the kafka-python package. The Kafka messages are serialized as Json, but are not associated with a schema as there was not an integrated schema registry. Later we discussed how producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve in Part 5. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to enhance the existing applications by integrating AWS Glue Schema Registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-22-kafka-development-with-docker-part-7/featured.png" length="57175" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 6 Kafka Connect with Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/</guid><description>In Part 3, we developed a data ingestion pipeline with fake online order data using Kafka Connect source and sink connectors. Schemas are not enabled on both of them as there was not an integrated schema registry. Later we discussed how producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve in Part 5. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to enhance the existing data ingestion pipeline by integrating AWS Glue Schema Registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-15-kafka-development-with-docker-part-6/featured.png" length="60354" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 5 Glue Schema Registry</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/</guid><description>As described in the Confluent document, Schema Registry provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the Glue Schema Registry supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and AWS Lambda.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-08-kafka-development-with-docker-part-5/featured.png" length="51170" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 2 Develop Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we reviewed Kafka connectors focusing on AWS services integration. Among the available connectors, the suite of Apache Camel Kafka connectors and the Kinesis Kafka connector from the AWS Labs can be effective for building data ingestion pipelines on AWS. In this post, I will illustrate how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker. Fake order data will be generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector will be configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="87044" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 4 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed Kafka Connect to stream data to/from a Kafka cluster. Kafka also includes the Producer/Consumer APIs that allow client applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java clients, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to develop producer/consumer applications using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-01-kafka-development-with-docker-part-4/featured.png" length="75255" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 3 Kafka Connect</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-25-kafka-development-with-docker-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-25-kafka-development-with-docker-part-3/</guid><description>According to the documentation of Apache Kafka, Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems. It makes it simple to quickly define connectors that move large collections of data into and out of Kafka. Kafka Connect supports two types of connectors - source and sink. Source connectors are used to ingest messages from external systems into Kafka topics while messages are ingested into external systems form Kafka topics with sink connectors.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-25-kafka-development-with-docker-part-3/featured.png" length="69998" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 2 Management App</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-18-kafka-development-with-docker-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-18-kafka-development-with-docker-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous post, I illustrated how to create a topic and to produce/consume messages using the command utilities provided by Apache Kafka. It is not convenient, however, for example, when you consume serialised messages where their schemas are stored in a schema registry. Also, the utilities don&amp;rsquo;t support to browse or manage related resources such as connectors and schemas. Therefore, a Kafka management app can be a good companion for development, which helps monitor and manage resources on an easy-to-use user interface.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-18-kafka-development-with-docker-part-2/featured.png" length="59675" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How I Prepared for Confluent Certified Developer for Apache Kafka as a Non-Java Developer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-11-how-i-prepared-for-ccdak/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-11-how-i-prepared-for-ccdak/</guid><description>I recently obtained the Confluent Certified Developer for Apache Kafka (CCDAK) certification. It focuses on knowledge of developing applications that work with Kafka, and is targeted to developers and solutions architects. As it assumes Java APIs for development and testing, I am contacted to share how I prepared for it as a non-Java developer from time to time. I thought it would be better to write a post to summarise how I did it rather than answering to them individually.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-11-how-i-prepared-for-ccdak/featured.png" length="215227" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development with Docker - Part 1 Cluster Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m teaching myself modern data streaming architectures on AWS, and Apache Kafka is one of the key technologies, which can be used for messaging, activity tracking, stream processing and so on. While applications tend to be deployed to cloud, it can be much easier if we develop and test those with Docker and Docker Compose locally. As the series title indicates, I plan to publish articles that demonstrate Kafka and related tools in Dockerized environments.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-04-kafka-development-with-docker-part-1/featured.png" length="98355" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 1 Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</guid><description>Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK) are two managed streaming services offered by AWS. Many resources on the web indicate Kinesis Data Streams is better when it comes to integrating with AWS services. However, it is not necessarily the case with the help of Kafka Connect. According to the documentation of Apache Kafka, Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="22272" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Self-managed Blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-24-self-hosted-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-24-self-hosted-blog/</guid><description>I started blogging in 2014. At first, it was based on a simple Jekyll theme that supports posting Markdown files, which are converted from R Markdown files. Most of my work was in R at that time and the simple theme was good enough, and it was hosted via GitHub Pages. It was around 2018 when I changed my blog with a single page application, built by Vue.js and hosted on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-24-self-hosted-blog/featured.png" length="41850" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Integrate Glue Schema Registry with Your Python Kafka App</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</guid><description>As Kafka producer and consumer apps are decoupled, they operate on Kafka topics rather than communicating with each other directly. As described in the Confluent document, Schema Registry provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the Glue Schema Registry supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and AWS Lambda.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/featured.png" length="46040" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 2 MSK and Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</guid><description>In Part 1, we discussed a streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless. Athena provides the MSK connector to enable SQL queries on Apache Kafka topics directly, and it can also facilitate the extraction of insights without setting up an additional pipeline to store data into S3. In this post, we discuss how to update the streaming ingestion solution so that data in the Kafka topic can be queried by Athena instead of Redshift.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/featured.png" length="43403" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 1 MSK and Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform. Previously loading data from Kafka into Redshift and Athena usually required Kafka connectors (e.g. Amazon Redshift Sink Connector and Amazon S3 Sink Connector). Recently these AWS services provide features to ingest data from Kafka directly, which facilitates a simpler architecture that achieves low-latency and high-speed ingestion of streaming data. In part 1 of the simplify streaming ingestion on AWS series, we discuss how to develop an end-to-end streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/featured.png" length="32864" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How to configure Kafka consumers to seek offsets by timestamp</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/</guid><description>Normally we consume Kafka messages from the beginning/end of a topic or last committed offsets. For backfilling or troubleshooting, however, we need to consume messages from a certain timestamp occasionally. The Kafka consumer class of the kafka-python package has a method to seek a particular offset for a topic partition. Therefore, if we know which topic partition to choose e.g. by assigning a topic partition, we can easily override the fetch offset.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-01-10-kafka-consumer-seek-offsets/featured.png" length="47217" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 5 Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue, EMR on EC2 and EMR on EKS are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/featured.png" length="91796" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 4 EMR on EKS</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue and EMR on EC2 are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/featured.png" length="91067" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 3 EMR on EC2</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless and Glue are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/featured.png" length="91067" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 2 Glue</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. A demo data project that targets Redshift Serverless is illustrated as well. In part 2 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on AWS Glue.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/featured.png" length="90647" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 1 Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on Redshift Serverless. Subsets of IMDb data are used as source and data models are developed in multiple layers according to the dbt best practices.
Part 1 Redshift (this post) Part 2 Glue Part 3 EMR on EC2 Part 4 EMR on EKS Part 5 Athena Motivation In our experience delivering data solutions for our customers, we have observed a desire to move away from a centralised team function, responsible for the data collection, analysis and reporting, towards shifting this responsibility to an organisation&amp;rsquo;s lines of business (LOB) teams.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/featured.png" length="97234" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Remotely Using Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</guid><description>When we develop a Spark application on EMR, we can use docker for local development or notebooks via EMR Studio (or EMR Notebooks). However, the local development option is not viable if the size of data is large. Also, I am not a fan of notebooks as it is not possible to utilise the features my editor supports such as syntax highlighting, autocomplete and code formatting. Moreover, it is not possible to organise code into modules and to perform unit testing properly with that option.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/featured.png" length="72448" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Manage EMR on EKS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</guid><description>Amazon EMR on EKS is a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on EKS. While eksctl is popular for working with Amazon EKS clusters, it has limitations when it comes to building infrastructure that integrates multiple AWS services. Also, it is not straightforward to update EKS cluster resources incrementally with it. On the other hand Terraform can be an effective tool for managing infrastructure that includes not only EKS and EMR virtual clusters but also other AWS resources.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/featured.png" length="67936" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Revisit AWS Lambda Invoke Function Operator of Apache Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular workflow management platform. A wide range of AWS services are integrated with the platform by Amazon AWS Operators. AWS Lambda is one of the integrated services, and it can be used to develop workflows efficiently. The current Lambda Operator, however, just invokes a Lambda function, and it can fail to report the invocation result of a function correctly and to record the exact error message from failure.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="24814" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Application Model (SAM) for Data Professionals</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-07-18-sam-for-data-professionals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-07-18-sam-for-data-professionals/</guid><description>AWS Lambda provides serverless computing capabilities, and it can be used for performing validation or light processing/transformation of data. Moreover, with its integration with more than 140 AWS services, it facilitates building complex systems employing event-driven architectures. There are many ways to build serverless applications and one of the most efficient ways is using specialised frameworks such as the AWS Serverless Application Model (SAM) and Serverless Framework. In this post, I’ll demonstrate how to build a serverless data processing application using SAM.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-07-18-sam-for-data-professionals/featured.png" length="22838" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Warehousing ETL Demo with Apache Iceberg on EMR Local Environment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/</guid><description>Unlike traditional Data Lake, new table formats (Iceberg, Hudi and Delta Lake) support features that can be used to apply data warehousing patterns, which can bring a way to be rescued from Data Swamp. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to implement ETL using retail analytics data. It has two dimension data (user and product) and a single fact data (order). The dimension data sets have different ETL strategies depending on whether to track historical changes.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/featured.png" length="43604" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Locally Using Docker</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/</guid><description>[UPDATE 2023-12-07]
I wrote a new post that simplifies the Spark configuration dramatically. Besides, the log configuration is based on Log4J2, which applies to newer Spark versions. Moreover, the container is configured to run the Spark History Server, and it allows us to debug and diagnose completed and running Spark applications. I recommend referring to the new post. Amazon EMR is a managed service that simplifies running Apache Spark on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/featured.png" length="25693" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 2 MSK Deployment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution with a schema registry. A local development environment is set up using Docker Compose. The Debezium and Confluent S3 connectors are deployed with the Confluent Avro converter and the Apicurio registry is used as the schema registry service. A quick example is shown to illustrate how schema evolution can be managed by the schema registry. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll build the solution on AWS using MSK, MSK Connect, Aurora PostgreSQL and ECS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</guid><description>When we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution in one of the earlier posts, we used the JSON converter that comes with Kafka Connect. We optionally enabled the key and value schemas and the topic messages include those schemas together with payload. It seems to be convenient at first as the messages are saved into S3 on their own. However, it became cumbersome when we tried to use the DeltaStreamer utility.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Your Development on AWS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</guid><description>When I wrote my data lake demo series (part 1, part 2 and part 3) recently, I used an Aurora PostgreSQL, MSK and EMR cluster. All of them were deployed to private subnets and dedicated infrastructure was created using CloudFormation. Using the infrastructure as code (IaC) tool helped a lot, but it resulted in creating 7 CloudFormation stacks, which was a bit harder to manage in the end. Then I looked into how to simplify building infrastructure and managing resources on AWS and decided to use Terraform instead.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/featured.png" length="46253" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>EMR on EKS by Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</guid><description>EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on Amazon EKS. While a wide range of open source big data components are available in EMR on EC2, only Apache Spark is available in EMR on EKS. It is more flexible, however, that applications of different EMR versions can be run in multiple availability zones on either EC2 or Fargate.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/featured.png" length="76740" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Lake Demo using Change Data Capture (CDC) on AWS – Part 3 Implement Data Lake</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-19-datalake-demo-part3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-19-datalake-demo-part3/</guid><description>In the previous post, we created a VPC that has private and public subnets in 2 availability zones in order to build and deploy the data lake solution on AWS. NAT instances are created to forward outbound traffic to the internet and a VPN bastion host is set up to facilitate deployment. An Aurora PostgreSQL cluster is deployed to host the source database and a Python command line app is used to create the database.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-19-datalake-demo-part3/featured.png" length="164526" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Lake Demo using Change Data Capture (CDC) on AWS – Part 2 Implement CDC</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-12-datalake-demo-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-12-datalake-demo-part2/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed a data lake solution where data ingestion is performed using change data capture (CDC) and the output files are upserted to an Apache Hudi table. Being registered to Glue Data Catalog, it can be used for ad-hoc queries and report/dashboard creation. The Northwind database is used as the source database and, following the transactional outbox pattern, order-related changes are _upserted _to an outbox table by triggers.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-12-datalake-demo-part2/featured.png" length="164526" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Lake Demo using Change Data Capture (CDC) on AWS – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-05-datalake-demo-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-05-datalake-demo-part1/</guid><description>Change data capture (CDC) is a proven data integration pattern that has a wide range of applications. Among those, data replication to data lakes is a good use case in data engineering. Coupled with best-in-breed data lake formats such as Apache Hudi, we can build an efficient data replication solution. This is the first post of the data lake demo series. Over time, we&amp;rsquo;ll build a data lake that uses CDC.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-05-datalake-demo-part1/featured.png" length="164526" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Local Development of AWS Glue 3.0 and Later</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</guid><description>In an earlier post, I demonstrated how to set up a local development environment for AWS Glue 1.0 and 2.0 using a docker image that is published by the AWS Glue team and the Visual Studio Code Remote – Containers extension. Recently AWS Glue 3.0 was released, but a docker image for this version is not published. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate how to create a development environment for AWS Glue 3.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/featured.png" length="30923" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Yet another serverless solution for invoking AWS Lambda at a sub-minute frequency</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/</guid><description>Triggering a Lambda function by an EventBridge Events rule can be used as a _serverless _replacement of cron job. The highest frequency of it is one invocation per minute so that it cannot be used directly if you need to schedule a Lambda function more frequently. For example, it may be refreshing an application with real time metrics from an Amazon Connect instance where some metrics are updated every 15 seconds.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-10-13-lambda-schedule/featured.png" length="46921" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Glue Local Development with Docker and Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</guid><description>As described in the product page, AWS Glue is a serverless data integration service that makes it easy to discover, prepare, and combine data for analytics, machine learning, and application development. For development, a development endpoint is recommended, but it can be costly, inconvenient or unavailable (for Glue 2.0). The AWS Glue team published a Docker image that includes the AWS Glue binaries and all the dependencies packaged together. After inspecting it, I find some modifications are necessary in order to build a development environment on it.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/featured.png" length="19535" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Adding Authorization to a Graphql API</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/</guid><description>Authorization is the mechanism that controls who can do what on which resource in an application. Although it is a critical part of an application, there are limited resources available on how to build authorization into an app effectively. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be illustrating how to set up authorization in a GraphQL API using a custom directive and Oso, an open-source authorization library. This tutorial covers the NodeJS variant of Oso, but it also supports Python and other languages.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-07-20-graphql-api-authorization/featured.png" length="52143" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Thoughts on Apache Airflow AWS Lambda Operator</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular open-source workflow management platform. Typically tasks run remotely by Celery workers for scalability. In AWS, however, scalability can also be achieved using serverless computing services in a simpler way. For example, the ECS Operator allows to run dockerized tasks and, with the Fargate launch type, they can run in a serverless environment.
The ECS Operator alone is not sufficient because it can take up to several minutes to pull a Docker image and to set up network interface (for the case of Fargate launch type).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="44994" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Dynamic Routing and Centralized Auth with Traefik, Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/</guid><description>Ingress in Kubernetes exposes HTTP and HTTPS routes from outside the cluster to services within the cluster. By setting rules, it routes requests to appropriate services (precisely requests are sent to individual Pods by Ingress Controller). Rules can be set up dynamically and I find it&amp;rsquo;s more efficient compared to traditional reverse proxy.
Traefik is a modern HTTP reverse proxy and load balancer and it can be used as a Kubernetes Ingress Controller.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-29-traefik-example/featured.png" length="139790" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Distributed Task Queue with Python and R Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/</guid><description>While I&amp;rsquo;m looking into Apache Airflow, a workflow management tool, I thought it would be beneficial to get some understanding of how Celery works. To do so, I built a simple web service that sends tasks to Celery workers and collects the results from them. FastAPI is used for developing the web service and Redis is used for the message broker and result backend. During the development, I thought it would be possible to implement similar functionality in R with Rserve.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-15-task-queue/featured.png" length="51615" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Linux Dev Environment on Windows</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</guid><description>I use Linux containers a lot for development. Having Windows computers at home and work, I used to use Linux VMs on VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad option but it requires a lot of resources. Recently, after my home computer was updated, I was not able to start my hypervisor anymore. Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t like huge resource consumption of it so that I began to look for a different development environment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/featured.png" length="187978" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Local Development with LocalStack</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</guid><description>LocalStack provides an easy-to-use test/mocking framework for developing AWS applications. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to utilize LocalStack for development using a web service.
Specifically a simple web service built with Flask-RestPlus is used. It supports simple CRUD operations against a database table. It is set that SQS and Lambda are used for creating and updating a record. When a POST or PUT request is made, the service sends a message to a SQS queue and directly returns 204 reponse.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/featured.png" length="164886" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Cronicle Multi Server Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/</guid><description>Accroding to the project GitHub repository,
Cronicle is a multi-server task scheduler and runner, with a web based front-end UI. It handles both scheduled, repeating and on-demand jobs, targeting any number of slave servers, with real-time stats and live log viewer.
By default, Cronicle is configured to launch a single master server - task scheduling is controlled by the master server. For high availability, it is important that another server takes the role of master when the existing master server fails.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-19-cronicle-multi-server-setup/featured.png" length="64396" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Shiny to Vue.js</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2018-05-26-shiny-to-vue.js/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2018-05-26-shiny-to-vue.js/</guid><description>In the last post, the async feature of Shiny was discussed. Although it is a remarkable step forward to web development in R, it is not to the full extent that a Javascript application can bring. In fact, (long running) requests of a user (or session) are not impacted by those of other users (or sessions) but, for a given user, all requests are handled sequentially. On the other hand, it is not the case for a Javascript-backed app where all requests are processed asynchronously.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2018-05-26-shiny-to-vue.js/featured.png" length="247205" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Async Shiny and Its Limitation</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2018-05-19-asyn-shiny-and-its-limitation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2018-05-19-asyn-shiny-and-its-limitation/</guid><description>A Shiny app is served by one (single-threaded blocking) process by Open Source Shiny Server. This causes a scalability issue because all requests are handled one by one in a queue. Recently the creator of Shiny introduced the promises package, which brings asynchronous programming capabilities to R. This is a remarkable step forward to web development in R.
In this post, it&amp;rsquo;ll be demonstrated how to implement the async feature of Shiny.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2018-05-19-asyn-shiny-and-its-limitation/featured.png" length="247205" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>API Development with R Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-19-api-development-with-r-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-19-api-development-with-r-2/</guid><description>In Part I, it is discussed how to serve an R function with plumber, Rserve and rApache. In this post, the APIs are deployed in a Docker container and, after showing example requests, their performance is compared. The rocker/r-ver:3.4 is used as the base image and each of the APIs is added to it. For simplicity, the APIs are served by Supervisor. For performance testing, Locust is used. The source of this post can be found in this GitHub repository.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-19-api-development-with-r-2/featured.png" length="367256" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>API Development with R Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-18-api-development-with-r-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-18-api-development-with-r-1/</guid><description>API is an effective way of distributing analysis outputs to external clients. When it comes to API development with R, however, there are not many choices. Probably development would be made with plumber, Rserve, rApache or OpenCPU if a client or bridge layer to R is not considered.
This is 2 part series in relation to API development with R. In this post, serving an R function with plumber, Rserve and rApache is discussed.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-11-18-api-development-with-r-1/featured.png" length="367256" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part IV - Serving R ML Model via S3</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</guid><description>In the previous posts, it is discussed how to package/deploy an R model with AWS Lambda and to expose the Lambda function via Amazon API Gateway. Main benefits of serverless architecture is cost-effectiveness and being hassle-free from provisioning/managing servers. While the API returns a predicted admission status value given GRE, GPA and Rank, there is an issue if it is served within a web application: Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS). This post discusses how to resolve this issue by updating API configuration and the Lambda function handler with a simple web application.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/featured.png" length="225463" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part III - Exposing R ML Model via APIG</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</guid><description>In Part I of this series, R and necessary libraries/packages together with a Lambda function handler are packaged and saved to Amazon S3. Then, in Part II, the package is deployed at AWS Lambda after creating and assigning a role to the Lambda function. Although the Lambda function can be called via the Invoke API, it&amp;rsquo;ll be much more useful if the function can be called as a web service (or API).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/featured.png" length="173293" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part II - Deploying R ML Model via Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</guid><description>In the previous post, serverless event-driven application development is introduced. Also how to package R, necessary libraries/packages and a Lambda function handler is discussed. No need of provisioning/managing servers is one of the key benefits of the architecture. It is also a cost-effective way of delivering a data product as functions are executed on-demand rather than in servers that run 24/7. Furthermore AWS Lambda free tier includes 1M free requests per month and 400,000 GB-seconds of compute time per month, which is available to both existing and new AWS customers indefinitely.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part I - Packaging R ML Model for Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[Let say you&rsquo;ve got a prediction model built in R and you&rsquo;d like to productionize it, for example, by serving it in a web application. One way is exposing the model through an API that returns the predicted result as a web service. However there are many issues. Firstly R is not a language for API development although there may be some ways - eg the plumber package. More importantly developing an API is not the end of the story as the API can&rsquo;t be served in a production system if it is not deployed/managed/upgraded/patched/&hellip; appropriately in a server or if it is not scalable, protected via authentication/authorization and so on.]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Shiny Open Source - Render Multiple Pages</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-06-27-shiny-open-source-render-multiple-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-06-27-shiny-open-source-render-multiple-pages/</guid><description>R Shiny applications are served as a single page application and it is not built to render multiple pages. There are benefits of rendering multiple pages such as code management and implement authentication. In this page, we discuss how to implement multi-page rendering in a Shiny app.
As indicated above, Shiny is not designed to render multiple pages and, in general, the UI is rendered on the fly as defined in ui.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Shiny Open Source - Internal Load Balancing</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-05-23-shiny-open-source-internal-load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-05-23-shiny-open-source-internal-load-balancing/</guid><description>Shiny is an interesting web framework that helps create a web application quickly. If it targets a large number of users, however, there are several limitations and it is so true when the open source version of Shiny is in use. It would be possible to tackle down some of the limitations with the enterprise version but it is not easy to see enough examples of Shiny applications in production environment.</description></item><item><title>Asynchronous Processing Using Job Queue</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-05-12-asynchronous-processing-using-job-queue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-05-12-asynchronous-processing-using-job-queue/</guid><description>In this post, a way to overcome one of R&amp;rsquo;s limitations (lack of multi-threading) is discussed by job queuing using the jobqueue package - a generic asynchronous job queue implementation for R. See the package description below.
The jobqueue package is meant to provide an easy-to-use interface that allows to queue computations for background evaluation while the calling R session remains responsive. It is based on a 1-node socket cluster from the parallel package.</description></item><item><title>Boost SparkR with Hive</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-04-30-boost-sparkr-with-hive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-04-30-boost-sparkr-with-hive/</guid><description>In the previous post, it is demonstrated how to start SparkR in local and cluster mode. While SparkR is in active development, it is yet to fully support Spark&amp;rsquo;s key libraries such as MLlib and Spark Streaming. Even, as a data processing engine, this R API is still limited as it is not possible to manipulate RDDs directly but only via Spark SQL/DataFrame API. As can be checked in the API doc, SparkR rebuilds many existing R functions to work with Spark DataFrame and notably it borrows some functions from the dplyr package.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start SparkR in Local and Cluster Mode</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-03-02-quick-start-sparkr-in-local-and-cluster-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-03-02-quick-start-sparkr-in-local-and-cluster-mode/</guid><description>In the previous post, a Spark cluster is set up using 2 VirtualBox Ubuntu guests. While this is a viable option for many, it is not always for others. For those who find setting-up such a cluster is not convenient, there&amp;rsquo;s still another option, which is relying on the local mode of Spark. In this post, a BitBucket repository is introduced, which is a R project that includes Spark 1.6.0 Pre-built for Hadoop 2.</description></item><item><title>Spark Cluster Setup on VirtualBox</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-02-22-spark-cluster-setup-on-virtualbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-02-22-spark-cluster-setup-on-virtualbox/</guid><description>We discuss how to set up a Spark cluser between 2 Ubuntu guests. Firstly it begins with machine preparation. Once a machine is baked, its image file (VDI) is be copied for the second one. Then how to launch a cluster by standalone mode is discussed. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Machine preparation If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, I recommend reading as it introduces Putty as well. Also, as Spark need Java Development Kit (JDK), you may need to apt-get it first - see this tutorial for further details.</description></item><item><title>Quick Test to Wrap Python in R</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</guid><description>As mentioned in an earlier post, things that are not easy in R can be relatively simple in other languages. Another example would be connecting to Amazon Web Services. In relation to s3, although there are a number of existing packages, many of them seem to be deprecated, premature or platform-dependent. (I consider the cloudyr project looks promising though.)
If there isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive R-way of doing something yet, it may be necessary to create it from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python for R Users</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</guid><description>There seem to be growing interest in Python in the R cummunity. While there can be a range of opinions about using R over Python (or vice versa) for exploratory data analysis, fitting statistical/machine learning algorithms and so on, I consider one of the strongest attractions of using Python comes from the fact that Python is a general purpose programming language. As more developers are involved in, it can provide a way to get jobs done easily, which can be tricky in R.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</guid><description>When I bagan to teach myself C# 3 years ago, I only had some experience in interactive analysis tools such as MATLAB and R - I didn&amp;rsquo;t consider R as a programming language at that time. The general purpose programming language shares some common features (data type, loop, if&amp;hellip;) but it is rather different in the way how code is written/organized, which is object oriented. Therefore, while it was not a problem to grap the common features, it took quite some time to understand and keep my code in an object oriented way.</description></item><item><title>Setup Random Seeds on Caret Package</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-05-30-setup-random-seeds-on-caret-package/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-05-30-setup-random-seeds-on-caret-package/</guid><description>A short while ago I had a chance to perform analysis using the caret package. One of the requirements is to run it parallelly and to work in both Windows and Linux. The requirement can be met by using the parallel and doParallel packages as the caret package trains a model using the foreach package if clusters are registered by the doParallel package - further details about how to implement parallel processing on a single machine can be found in earlier posts (Link 1, Link 2 and Link 3).</description></item><item><title>Packaging Analysis</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-24-packaging-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-24-packaging-analysis/</guid><description>When I imagine a workflow, it is performing the same or similar tasks regularly (daily or weekly) in an automated way. Although those tasks can be executed in a script or a *source()*d script, it may not be easy to maintain separate scripts while the size of tasks gets bigger or if they have to be executed in different machines. In academia, reproducible research shares similar ideas but the level of reproducibility introduced in Gandrud, 2013 may not suffice in a business environment as the focus is documenting in a reproducible way.</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part III</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-19-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-19-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-3/</guid><description>In the previous posts, two groups of ways to implement parallel processing on a single machine are introduced. The first group is provided by the snow or parallel package and the functions are an extension of lapply() (LINK). The second group is based on an extension of the for construct (foreach, %dopar% and %:%). The foreach construct is provided by the foreach package while clusters are made and registered by the parallel and doParallel packages respectively (LINK).</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-17-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-17-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-2/</guid><description>In the previous article, parallel processing on a single machine using the snow and parallel packages are introduced. The four functions are an extension of lapply() with an additional argument that specifies a cluster object. In spite of their effectiveness and ease of use, there may be cases where creating a function that can be sent into clusters is not easy or looping may be more natural. In this article, another way of implementing parallel processing on a single machine is introduced using the foreach and doParallel packages where clusters are created by the parallel package.</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-14-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-14-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-1/</guid><description>Lack of multi-threading and memory limitation are two outstanding weaknesses of base R. In fact, however, if the size of data is not so large that it can be read in RAM, the former would be relatively easily handled by parallel processing, provided that multiple processors are equipped. This article introduces to a way of implementing parallel processing on a single machine using the snow and parallel packages - the examples are largely based on McCallum and Weston (2012).</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part VI</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-07-tree-based-methods-6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-07-tree-based-methods-6/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III Part IV Part V Part VI (this post) A regression tree is evaluated using bagged trees in the previous article. In this article, the response variable of the same data set is converted into a binary factor variable and a classification tree is evaluated by comparing to bagged trees&amp;rsquo; individual oob/test errors, cumulative oob/test errors and variable importance measures.
Before getting started, note that the source of the classes can be found in this gist and, together with the relevant packages (see tags), it requires a utility function (bestParam()) that can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part V</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-05-tree-based-methods-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-05-tree-based-methods-5/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III Part IV Part V (this post) Part VI This article evaluates a single regression tree&amp;rsquo;s performance by comparing to bagged trees&amp;rsquo; individual oob/test errors, cumulative oob/test errors and variable importance measures.
Before getting started, note that the source of the classes can be found in this gist and, together with the relevant packages (see tags), it requires a utility function (bestParam()) that can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part IV</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-15-tree-based-methods-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-15-tree-based-methods-4/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III Part IV (this post) Part V Part VI While the last three articles illustrated the CART model for both classification (with equal/unequal costs) and regression tasks, this article is rather technical as it compares three packages: rpart, caret and mlr. For those who are not familiar with the last two packages, they are wrappers (or frameworks) that implement a range of models (or algorithms) in a unified way.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part III</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-14-tree-based-methods-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-14-tree-based-methods-3/</guid><description>Part I Part II Part III (this post) Part IV Part V Part VI While classification tasks are implemented in the last two articles (Part I and Part II), a regression task is the topic of this article. While the caret package selects the tuning parameter (cp) that minimizes the error (RMSE), the rpart packages recommends the 1-SE rule, which selects the smallest tree within 1 standard error of the minimum cross validation error (xerror).</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-08-tree-based-methods-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-08-tree-based-methods-2/</guid><description>Part I Part II (this post) Part III Part IV Part V Part VI In the previous article (Tree Based Methods in R - Part I), a decision tree is created on the Carseats data which is in the chapter 8 lab of ISLR. In that article, potentially asymetric costs due to misclassification are not taken into account. When unbalance between false positive and false negative can have a significant impact, it can be explicitly adjusted either by altering prior (or empirical) probabilities or by adding a loss matrix.</description></item><item><title>Tree Based Methods in R - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-01-tree-based-methods-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-02-01-tree-based-methods-1/</guid><description>Part I (this post) Part II Part III Part IV Part V Part VI This is the first article about tree based methods using R. Carseats data in the chapter 8 lab of ISLR is used to perform classification analysis. Unlike the lab example, the rpart package is used to fit the CART model on the data and the caret package is used for tuning the pruning parameter (cp).</description></item><item><title>Quick Trial of Adding Column</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-01-14-quick-trial-of-adding-column/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-01-14-quick-trial-of-adding-column/</guid><description>This is a quick trial of adding overall and conditional (by user) average columns in a data frame. base,plyr,dplyr,data.table,dplyr + data.table packages are used. Personally I perfer dplyr + data.table - dplyr for comperhensive syntax and data.table for speed.
1## set up variables 2size &amp;lt;- 36000 3numUsers &amp;lt;- 4900 4# roughly each user has 7 sessions 5numSessions &amp;lt;- (numUsers / 7) - ((numUsers / 7) %% 1) 6 7## create data frame 8set.</description></item><item><title>Looping without for</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-17-looping-without-for/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-17-looping-without-for/</guid><description>Purely programming point of view, I consider for-loops would be better to be avoided in R as
the script can be more readable it is easier to handle errors Some articles on the web indicate that looping functions (or apply family of functions) don&amp;rsquo;t guarantee faster execution and sometimes even slower. Although, assuming that the experiments are correct, in my opinion, code readability itself is beneficial enough to avoid for-loops. Even worse, R&amp;rsquo;s dynamic typing system coupled with poor readability can result in a frustrating consequence as the code grows.</description></item><item><title>Short R Examples</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-03-short-r-examples/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-03-short-r-examples/</guid><description>As I don&amp;rsquo;t use R at work yet, I haven&amp;rsquo;t got enough chances to learn R by doing. Together with teaching myself machine learning with R, I consider it would be a good idea to collect examples on the web. Recently I have been visiting a Linkedin group called The R Project for Statistical Computing and suggesting scripts on data manipulation or programming topics. Actually I expected some of the topics may also be helpful to learn machine learning/statistics but, possibly due to lack of understaning of the topics in context, I&amp;rsquo;ve found only a few - it may be necessary to look for another source.</description></item><item><title>Summarise Stock Returns from Multiple Files</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-27-summarise-stock-returns-from-multiple-files/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-27-summarise-stock-returns-from-multiple-files/</guid><description><![CDATA[This post is a slight extension of the previous two articles (Download Stock Data - Part I, Download Stock Data - Part II) and we discuss how to produce gross returns, standard deviation and correlation of multiple shares.
The following packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(reshape2) 5library(plyr) 6library(dplyr) The script begins with creating a data folder in the format of data_YYYY-MM-DD.
1# create data folder 2dataDir &lt;- paste0(&#34;data&#34;,&#34;_&#34;,format(Sys.Date(),&#34;%Y-%m-%d&#34;)) 3if(file.exists(dataDir)) { 4 unlink(dataDir, recursive = TRUE) 5 dir.]]></description></item><item><title>Download Stock Data - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-21-download-stock-data-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-21-download-stock-data-2/</guid><description>In an earlier article, a way to download stock price data files from Google, save it into a local drive and merge them into a single data frame. If files are not large, however, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be effective and, in this article, files are downloaded and merged internally.
The following packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(plyr) 5library(dplyr) Taking urls as file locations, files are directly read using llply and they are combined using rbind_all.</description></item><item><title>Download Stock Data - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-20-download-stock-data-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-20-download-stock-data-1/</guid><description>This article illustrates how to download stock price data files from Google, save it into a local drive and merge them into a single data frame. This script is slightly modified from a script which downloads RStudio package download log data. The original source can be found here.
First of all, the following three packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(plyr) 5library(dplyr) The script begins with creating a folder to save data files.</description></item></channel></rss>