<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>R on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/r/</link><description>Recent content in R on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2025 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Asynchronous Processing Using Job Queue</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-05-12-asynchronous-processing-using-job-queue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-05-12-asynchronous-processing-using-job-queue/</guid><description>In this post, a way to overcome one of R&amp;rsquo;s limitations (lack of multi-threading) is discussed by job queuing using the jobqueue package - a generic asynchronous job queue implementation for R. See the package description below.
The jobqueue package is meant to provide an easy-to-use interface that allows to queue computations for background evaluation while the calling R session remains responsive. It is based on a 1-node socket cluster from the parallel package.</description></item><item><title>Boost SparkR with Hive</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-04-30-boost-sparkr-with-hive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-04-30-boost-sparkr-with-hive/</guid><description>In the previous post, it is demonstrated how to start SparkR in local and cluster mode. While SparkR is in active development, it is yet to fully support Spark&amp;rsquo;s key libraries such as MLlib and Spark Streaming. Even, as a data processing engine, this R API is still limited as it is not possible to manipulate RDDs directly but only via Spark SQL/DataFrame API. As can be checked in the API doc, SparkR rebuilds many existing R functions to work with Spark DataFrame and notably it borrows some functions from the dplyr package.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start SparkR in Local and Cluster Mode</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-03-02-quick-start-sparkr-in-local-and-cluster-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-03-02-quick-start-sparkr-in-local-and-cluster-mode/</guid><description>In the previous post, a Spark cluster is set up using 2 VirtualBox Ubuntu guests. While this is a viable option for many, it is not always for others. For those who find setting-up such a cluster is not convenient, there&amp;rsquo;s still another option, which is relying on the local mode of Spark. In this post, a BitBucket repository is introduced, which is a R project that includes Spark 1.6.0 Pre-built for Hadoop 2.</description></item><item><title>Spark Cluster Setup on VirtualBox</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-02-22-spark-cluster-setup-on-virtualbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2016-02-22-spark-cluster-setup-on-virtualbox/</guid><description>We discuss how to set up a Spark cluser between 2 Ubuntu guests. Firstly it begins with machine preparation. Once a machine is baked, its image file (VDI) is be copied for the second one. Then how to launch a cluster by standalone mode is discussed. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Machine preparation If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, I recommend reading as it introduces Putty as well. Also, as Spark need Java Development Kit (JDK), you may need to apt-get it first - see this tutorial for further details.</description></item><item><title>Quick Test to Wrap Python in R</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-11-21-quick-test-to-wrap-python-in-r/</guid><description>As mentioned in an earlier post, things that are not easy in R can be relatively simple in other languages. Another example would be connecting to Amazon Web Services. In relation to s3, although there are a number of existing packages, many of them seem to be deprecated, premature or platform-dependent. (I consider the cloudyr project looks promising though.)
If there isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive R-way of doing something yet, it may be necessary to create it from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Packaging Analysis</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-24-packaging-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-24-packaging-analysis/</guid><description>When I imagine a workflow, it is performing the same or similar tasks regularly (daily or weekly) in an automated way. Although those tasks can be executed in a script or a *source()*d script, it may not be easy to maintain separate scripts while the size of tasks gets bigger or if they have to be executed in different machines. In academia, reproducible research shares similar ideas but the level of reproducibility introduced in Gandrud, 2013 may not suffice in a business environment as the focus is documenting in a reproducible way.</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part III</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-19-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-19-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-3/</guid><description>In the previous posts, two groups of ways to implement parallel processing on a single machine are introduced. The first group is provided by the snow or parallel package and the functions are an extension of lapply() (LINK). The second group is based on an extension of the for construct (foreach, %dopar% and %:%). The foreach construct is provided by the foreach package while clusters are made and registered by the parallel and doParallel packages respectively (LINK).</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-17-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-17-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-2/</guid><description>In the previous article, parallel processing on a single machine using the snow and parallel packages are introduced. The four functions are an extension of lapply() with an additional argument that specifies a cluster object. In spite of their effectiveness and ease of use, there may be cases where creating a function that can be sent into clusters is not easy or looping may be more natural. In this article, another way of implementing parallel processing on a single machine is introduced using the foreach and doParallel packages where clusters are created by the parallel package.</description></item><item><title>Parallel Processing on Single Machine - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-14-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-03-14-parallel-processing-on-single-machine-1/</guid><description>Lack of multi-threading and memory limitation are two outstanding weaknesses of base R. In fact, however, if the size of data is not so large that it can be read in RAM, the former would be relatively easily handled by parallel processing, provided that multiple processors are equipped. This article introduces to a way of implementing parallel processing on a single machine using the snow and parallel packages - the examples are largely based on McCallum and Weston (2012).</description></item><item><title>Quick Trial of Adding Column</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-01-14-quick-trial-of-adding-column/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-01-14-quick-trial-of-adding-column/</guid><description>This is a quick trial of adding overall and conditional (by user) average columns in a data frame. base,plyr,dplyr,data.table,dplyr + data.table packages are used. Personally I perfer dplyr + data.table - dplyr for comperhensive syntax and data.table for speed.
1## set up variables 2size &amp;lt;- 36000 3numUsers &amp;lt;- 4900 4# roughly each user has 7 sessions 5numSessions &amp;lt;- (numUsers / 7) - ((numUsers / 7) %% 1) 6 7## create data frame 8set.</description></item><item><title>Looping without for</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-17-looping-without-for/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-17-looping-without-for/</guid><description>Purely programming point of view, I consider for-loops would be better to be avoided in R as
the script can be more readable it is easier to handle errors Some articles on the web indicate that looping functions (or apply family of functions) don&amp;rsquo;t guarantee faster execution and sometimes even slower. Although, assuming that the experiments are correct, in my opinion, code readability itself is beneficial enough to avoid for-loops. Even worse, R&amp;rsquo;s dynamic typing system coupled with poor readability can result in a frustrating consequence as the code grows.</description></item><item><title>Short R Examples</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-03-short-r-examples/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-12-03-short-r-examples/</guid><description>As I don&amp;rsquo;t use R at work yet, I haven&amp;rsquo;t got enough chances to learn R by doing. Together with teaching myself machine learning with R, I consider it would be a good idea to collect examples on the web. Recently I have been visiting a Linkedin group called The R Project for Statistical Computing and suggesting scripts on data manipulation or programming topics. Actually I expected some of the topics may also be helpful to learn machine learning/statistics but, possibly due to lack of understaning of the topics in context, I&amp;rsquo;ve found only a few - it may be necessary to look for another source.</description></item><item><title>Summarise Stock Returns from Multiple Files</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-27-summarise-stock-returns-from-multiple-files/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-27-summarise-stock-returns-from-multiple-files/</guid><description><![CDATA[This post is a slight extension of the previous two articles (Download Stock Data - Part I, Download Stock Data - Part II) and we discuss how to produce gross returns, standard deviation and correlation of multiple shares.
The following packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(reshape2) 5library(plyr) 6library(dplyr) The script begins with creating a data folder in the format of data_YYYY-MM-DD.
1# create data folder 2dataDir &lt;- paste0(&#34;data&#34;,&#34;_&#34;,format(Sys.Date(),&#34;%Y-%m-%d&#34;)) 3if(file.exists(dataDir)) { 4 unlink(dataDir, recursive = TRUE) 5 dir.]]></description></item><item><title>Download Stock Data - Part II</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-21-download-stock-data-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-21-download-stock-data-2/</guid><description>In an earlier article, a way to download stock price data files from Google, save it into a local drive and merge them into a single data frame. If files are not large, however, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be effective and, in this article, files are downloaded and merged internally.
The following packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(plyr) 5library(dplyr) Taking urls as file locations, files are directly read using llply and they are combined using rbind_all.</description></item><item><title>Download Stock Data - Part I</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-20-download-stock-data-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2014-11-20-download-stock-data-1/</guid><description>This article illustrates how to download stock price data files from Google, save it into a local drive and merge them into a single data frame. This script is slightly modified from a script which downloads RStudio package download log data. The original source can be found here.
First of all, the following three packages are used.
1library(knitr) 2library(lubridate) 3library(stringr) 4library(plyr) 5library(dplyr) The script begins with creating a folder to save data files.</description></item></channel></rss>