<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>OpenSearch on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/opensearch/</link><description>Recent content in OpenSearch on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2026 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/opensearch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</guid><description>The value of data can be maximised when it is used without delay. With Apache Flink, we can build streaming analytics applications that incorporate the latest events with low latency. In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that writes accumulated taxi rides data into an OpenSearch cluster. It aggregates the number of trips/passengers and trip durations by vendor ID for a window of 5 seconds. The data is then used to create a chart that monitors the status of taxi rides in the OpenSearch Dashboard.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/featured.png" length="112340" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 4 Develop Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</guid><description>[UPDATE 2025-10-01]
Bitnami&amp;rsquo;s public Docker images have been moved to the Bitnami Legacy repository. To ensure continued access and compatibility, please update your Docker image references accordingly.
For example:
bitnami/kafka:2.8.1 → bitnamilegacy/kafka:2.8.1 bitnami/zookeeper:3.7.0 → bitnamilegacy/zookeeper:3.7.0 bitnami/python:3.9.0 → bitnamilegacy/python:3.9.0 OpenSearch is a popular search and analytics engine and its use cases cover log analytics, real-time application monitoring, and clickstream analysis. OpenSearch can be deployed on its own or via Amazon OpenSearch Service.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/featured.png" length="61820" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>