<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Amazon Athena on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-athena/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon Athena on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-athena/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 2 MSK and Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
In Part 1, we discussed a streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless. Athena provides the MSK connector to enable SQL queries on Apache Kafka topics directly, and it can also facilitate the extraction of insights without setting up an additional pipeline to store data into S3. In this post, we discuss how to update the streaming ingestion solution so that data in the Kafka topic can be queried by Athena instead of Redshift.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/featured.png" length="43403" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 5 Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue, EMR on EC2 and EMR on EKS are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/featured.png" length="91796" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>