<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Integrate Schema Registry with MSK Connect on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/series/integrate-schema-registry-with-msk-connect/</link><description>Recent content in Integrate Schema Registry with MSK Connect on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/series/integrate-schema-registry-with-msk-connect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 2 MSK Deployment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
In the previous post, we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution with a schema registry. A local development environment is set up using Docker Compose. The Debezium and Confluent S3 connectors are deployed with the Confluent Avro converter and the Apicurio registry is used as the schema registry service. A quick example is shown to illustrate how schema evolution can be managed by the schema registry.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
When we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution in one of the earlier posts, we used the JSON converter that comes with Kafka Connect. We optionally enabled the key and value schemas and the topic messages include those schemas together with payload. It seems to be convenient at first as the messages are saved into S3 on their own.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>