<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>General on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Prepared for Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/</guid><description>I recently obtained the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) certification. CKAD has been developed by The Linux Foundation and the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), to help expand the Kubernetes ecosystem through standardized training and certification. Specifically this certification is for Kubernetes engineers, cloud engineers and other IT professionals responsible for building, deploying, and configuring cloud native applications with Kubernetes. In this post, I will summarise how I prepared for the exam by reviewing three online courses and two practice tests that I went through.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-12-how-i-prepared-for-ckad/featured.png" length="5945" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>How I Prepared for Confluent Certified Developer for Apache Kafka as a Non-Java Developer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-11-how-i-prepared-for-ccdak/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-11-how-i-prepared-for-ccdak/</guid><description>I recently obtained the Confluent Certified Developer for Apache Kafka (CCDAK) certification. It focuses on knowledge of developing applications that work with Kafka, and is targeted to developers and solutions architects. As it assumes Java APIs for development and testing, I am contacted to share how I prepared for it as a non-Java developer from time to time. I thought it would be better to write a post to summarise how I did it rather than answering to them individually.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-11-how-i-prepared-for-ccdak/featured.png" length="215227" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Self-managed Blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-24-self-hosted-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-24-self-hosted-blog/</guid><description>I started blogging in 2014. At first, it was based on a simple Jekyll theme that supports posting Markdown files, which are converted from R Markdown files. Most of my work was in R at that time and the simple theme was good enough, and it was hosted via GitHub Pages. It was around 2018 when I changed my blog with a single page application, built by Vue.js and hosted on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-24-self-hosted-blog/featured.png" length="41850" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python for R Users</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-09-some-thoughts-on-python-for-r-users/</guid><description>There seem to be growing interest in Python in the R cummunity. While there can be a range of opinions about using R over Python (or vice versa) for exploratory data analysis, fitting statistical/machine learning algorithms and so on, I consider one of the strongest attractions of using Python comes from the fact that Python is a general purpose programming language. As more developers are involved in, it can provide a way to get jobs done easily, which can be tricky in R.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Python</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2015-08-08-some-thoughts-on-python/</guid><description>When I bagan to teach myself C# 3 years ago, I only had some experience in interactive analysis tools such as MATLAB and R - I didn&amp;rsquo;t consider R as a programming language at that time. The general purpose programming language shares some common features (data type, loop, if&amp;hellip;) but it is rather different in the way how code is written/organized, which is object oriented. Therefore, while it was not a problem to grap the common features, it took quite some time to understand and keep my code in an object oriented way.</description></item></channel></rss>