<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Amazon OpenSearch Service on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-opensearch-service/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon OpenSearch Service on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-opensearch-service/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/</guid><description>The value of data can be maximised when it is used without delay. With Apache Flink, we can build streaming analytics applications that incorporate the latest events with low latency. In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that writes accumulated taxi rides data into an OpenSearch cluster. It aggregates the number of trips/passengers and trip durations by vendor ID for a window of 5 seconds. The data is then used to create a chart that monitors the status of taxi rides in the OpenSearch Dashboard.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-23-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-5/featured.png" length="112340" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 5 Deploy Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to develop a data pipeline from Apache Kafka into OpenSearch locally using Docker. The pipeline will be deployed on AWS using Amazon MSK, Amazon MSK Connect and Amazon OpenSearch Service using Terraform in this post. First the infrastructure will be deployed that covers a Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Virtual Private Network (VPN) server, MSK Cluster and OpenSearch domain. Then Kafka source and sink connectors will be deployed on MSK Connect, followed by performing quick data analysis.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/featured.png" length="85575" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</guid><description>Real Time Streaming with Amazon Kinesis is an AWS workshop that helps users build a streaming analytics application on AWS. Incoming events are stored in a number of streams of the Amazon Kinesis Data Streams service, and various other AWS services and tools are used to process and analyse data.
Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform, and it stores incoming events in topics. As part of learning real time streaming analytics on AWS, we can rebuild the analytics applications by replacing the Kinesis streams with Kafka topics.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/featured.png" length="138141" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>