<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Factor House Local on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/factor-house-local/</link><description>Recent content in Factor House Local on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2025 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/factor-house-local/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka Clients with Avro - Schema Registry and Order Events</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-05-27-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-avro-clients/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-05-27-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-avro-clients/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this post, we&rsquo;ll explore a practical example of building Kafka client applications using Kotlin, Apache Avro for data serialization, and Gradle for build management. We&rsquo;ll walk through the setup of a Kafka producer that generates mock order data and a consumer that processes these orders. This example highlights best practices such as schema management with Avro, robust error handling, and graceful shutdown, providing a solid foundation for your own Kafka-based projects. We&rsquo;ll dive into the build configuration, the Avro schema definition, utility functions for Kafka administration, and the core logic of both the producer and consumer applications.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-05-27-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-avro-clients/featured.png" length="76117" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Clients with JSON - Producing and Consuming Order Events</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-05-20-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-json-clients/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-05-20-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-json-clients/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post explores a Kotlin-based Kafka project, meticulously detailing the construction and operation of both a Kafka producer application, responsible for generating and sending order data, and a Kafka consumer application, designed to receive and process these orders. We&amp;rsquo;ll delve into each component, from build configuration to message handling, to understand how they work together in an event-driven system.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2025-05-20-kotlin-getting-started-kafka-json-clients/featured.png" length="97922" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>