<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>DBT for Effective Data Transformation on AWS on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/series/dbt-for-effective-data-transformation-on-aws/</link><description>Recent content in DBT for Effective Data Transformation on AWS on Jaehyeon's Personal Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/series/dbt-for-effective-data-transformation-on-aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 5 Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue, EMR on EC2 and EMR on EKS are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/featured.png" length="91796" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 4 EMR on EKS</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue and EMR on EC2 are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/featured.png" length="91067" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 3 EMR on EC2</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless and Glue are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/featured.png" length="91067" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 2 Glue</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. A demo data project that targets Redshift Serverless is illustrated as well. In part 2 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on AWS Glue.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/featured.png" length="90647" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 1 Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on Redshift Serverless. Subsets of IMDb data are used as source and data models are developed in multiple layers according to the dbt best practices.
Part 1 Redshift (this post) Part 2 Glue Part 3 EMR on EC2 Part 4 EMR on EKS Part 5 Athena Motivation In our experience delivering data solutions for our customers, we have observed a desire to move away from a centralised team function, responsible for the data collection, analysis and reporting, towards shifting this responsibility to an organisation&amp;rsquo;s lines of business (LOB) teams.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/featured.png" length="97234" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>