<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/series/kafka-flink-and-dynamodb-for-real-time-fraud-detection/</link><description>Recent content in Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2025 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/series/kafka-flink-and-dynamodb-for-real-time-fraud-detection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 2 Deployment via AWS Managed Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/</guid><description>This series aims to help those who are new to Apache Flink and Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink by re-implementing a simple fraud detection application that is discussed in an AWS workshop titled AWS Kafka and DynamoDB for real time fraud detection. In part 1, I demonstrated how to develop the application locally, and the app will be deployed via Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink in this post.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-09-14-fraud-detection-part-2/featured.png" length="66221" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka, Flink and DynamoDB for Real Time Fraud Detection - Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/</guid><description>[UPDATE 2025-10-01]
Bitnami&amp;rsquo;s public Docker images have been moved to the Bitnami Legacy repository. To ensure continued access and compatibility, please update your Docker image references accordingly.
For example:
bitnami/kafka:2.8.1 → bitnamilegacy/kafka:2.8.1 bitnami/zookeeper:3.7.0 → bitnamilegacy/zookeeper:3.7.0 bitnami/python:3.9.0 → bitnamilegacy/python:3.9.0 Apache Flink is an open-source, unified stream-processing and batch-processing framework. Its core is a distributed streaming data-flow engine that you can use to run real-time stream processing on high-throughput data sources. Currently, it is widely used to build applications for fraud/anomaly detection, rule-based alerting, business process monitoring, and continuous ETL to name a few.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-08-10-fraud-detection-part-1/featured.png" length="72929" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>