<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Minikube on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/minikube/</link><description>Recent content in Minikube on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/minikube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy Python Stream Processing App on Kubernetes - Part 2 Beam Pipeline on Flink Runner</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/</guid><description>In this post, we develop an Apache Beam pipeline using the Python SDK and deploy it on an Apache Flink cluster via the Apache Flink Runner. Same as Part I, we deploy a Kafka cluster using the Strimzi Operator on a minikube cluster as the pipeline uses Apache Kafka topics for its data source and sink. Then, we develop the pipeline as a Python package and add the package to a custom Docker image so that Python user code can be executed externally.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-06-06-beam-deploy-2/featured.png" length="58020" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Deploy Python Stream Processing App on Kubernetes - Part 1 PyFlink Application</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/</guid><description>Flink Kubernetes Operator acts as a control plane to manage the complete deployment lifecycle of Apache Flink applications. With the operator, we can simplify deployment and management of Python stream processing applications. In this series, we discuss how to deploy a PyFlink application and Python Apache Beam pipeline on the Flink Runner on Kubernetes.
In Part 1, we first deploy a Kafka cluster on a minikube cluster as the source and sink of the PyFlink application are Kafka topics.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-05-30-beam-deploy-1/featured.png" length="64457" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 3 Kafka Connect</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-11-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-11-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-3/</guid><description>Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems. It makes it simple to quickly define connectors that move large collections of data into and out of Kafka. In this post, we discuss how to set up a data ingestion pipeline using Kafka connectors. Fake customer and order data is ingested into Kafka topics using the MSK Data Generator. Also, we use the Confluent S3 sink connector to save the messages of the topics into a S3 bucket.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-11-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-3/featured.png" length="97270" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 2 Producer and Consumer</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/</guid><description>Apache Kafka has five core APIs, and we can develop applications to send/read streams of data to/from topics in a Kafka cluster using the producer and consumer APIs. While the main Kafka project maintains only the Java APIs, there are several open source projects that provide the Kafka client APIs in Python. In this post, we discuss how to develop Kafka client applications using the kafka-python package on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup Part 2 Producer and Consumer (this post) Part 3 Kafka Connect Kafka Client Apps We create Kafka producer and consumer apps using the kafka-python package.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-01-04-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-2/featured.png" length="75889" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Development on Kubernetes - Part 1 Cluster Setup</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is one of the key technologies for implementing data streaming architectures. Strimzi provides a way to run an Apache Kafka cluster and related resources on Kubernetes in various deployment configurations. In this series of posts, we will discuss how to create a Kafka cluster, to develop Kafka client applications in Python and to build a data pipeline using Kafka connectors on Kubernetes.
Part 1 Cluster Setup (this post) Part 2 Producer and Consumer Part 3 Kafka Connect Setup Kafka Cluster The Kafka cluster is deployed using the Strimzi Operator on a Minikube cluster.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-12-21-kafka-development-on-k8s-part-1/featured.png" length="108975" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Linux Dev Environment on Windows</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/</guid><description>I use Linux containers a lot for development. Having Windows computers at home and work, I used to use Linux VMs on VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad option but it requires a lot of resources. Recently, after my home computer was updated, I was not able to start my hypervisor anymore. Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t like huge resource consumption of it so that I began to look for a different development environment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-11-01-linux-on-windows/featured.png" length="187978" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>