<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Apache Camel on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/apache-camel/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Camel on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/apache-camel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</guid><description>Real Time Streaming with Amazon Kinesis is an AWS workshop that helps users build a streaming analytics application on AWS. Incoming events are stored in a number of streams of the Amazon Kinesis Data Streams service, and various other AWS services and tools are used to process and analyse data.
Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform, and it stores incoming events in topics. As part of learning real time streaming analytics on AWS, we can rebuild the analytics applications by replacing the Kinesis streams with Kafka topics.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/featured.png" length="138141" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 3 Deploy Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</guid><description>As part of investigating how to utilize Kafka Connect effectively for AWS services integration, I demonstrated how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker in Part 2. Fake order data was generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector was configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table. In this post, I will illustrate how to deploy the data ingestion applications using Amazon MSK and MSK Connect.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="76240" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 2 Develop Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we reviewed Kafka connectors focusing on AWS services integration. Among the available connectors, the suite of Apache Camel Kafka connectors and the Kinesis Kafka connector from the AWS Labs can be effective for building data ingestion pipelines on AWS. In this post, I will illustrate how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker. Fake order data will be generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector will be configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="87044" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>