<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>AWS Glue on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/aws-glue/</link><description>Recent content in AWS Glue on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/aws-glue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</guid><description>Real Time Streaming with Amazon Kinesis is an AWS workshop that helps users build a streaming analytics application on AWS. Incoming events are stored in a number of streams of the Amazon Kinesis Data Streams service, and various other AWS services and tools are used to process and analyse data.
Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform, and it stores incoming events in topics. As part of learning real time streaming analytics on AWS, we can rebuild the analytics applications by replacing the Kinesis streams with Kafka topics.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/featured.png" length="138141" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 2 Glue</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. A demo data project that targets Redshift Serverless is illustrated as well. In part 2 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on AWS Glue.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/featured.png" length="90647" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Local Development of AWS Glue 3.0 and Later</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</guid><description>In an earlier post, I demonstrated how to set up a local development environment for AWS Glue 1.0 and 2.0 using a docker image that is published by the AWS Glue team and the Visual Studio Code Remote – Containers extension. Recently AWS Glue 3.0 was released, but a docker image for this version is not published. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate how to create a development environment for AWS Glue 3.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/featured.png" length="30923" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Glue Local Development with Docker and Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</guid><description>As described in the product page, AWS Glue is a serverless data integration service that makes it easy to discover, prepare, and combine data for analytics, machine learning, and application development. For development, a development endpoint is recommended, but it can be costly, inconvenient or unavailable (for Glue 2.0). The AWS Glue team published a Docker image that includes the AWS Glue binaries and all the dependencies packaged together. After inspecting it, I find some modifications are necessary in order to build a development environment on it.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/featured.png" length="19535" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>