<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>GRPC on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/grpc/</link><description>Recent content in GRPC on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/grpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Beam Python Examples - Part 5 Call RPC Service in Batch using Stateless DoFn</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-09-18-beam-examples-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-09-18-beam-examples-5/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In the <a href="/blog/2024-08-15-beam-examples-4">previous post</a>, we developed an Apache Beam pipeline where the input data is augmented by an <strong>Remote Procedure Call (RPC)</strong> service. Each input element performs an RPC call and the output is enriched by the response. This is not an efficient way of accessing an external service provided that the service can accept more than one element. In this post, we discuss how to enhance the pipeline so that a single RPC call is made for a bundle of elements, which can save a significant amount time compared to making a call for each element.</p>]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-09-18-beam-examples-5/featured.png" length="95285" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Apache Beam Python Examples - Part 4 Call RPC Service for Data Augmentation</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-08-15-beam-examples-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-08-15-beam-examples-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post, we develop an Apache Beam pipeline where the input data is augmented by an &lt;strong>Remote Procedure Call (RPC)&lt;/strong> service. Each input element performs an RPC call and the output is enriched by the response. This is not an efficient way of accessing an external service provided that the service can accept more than one element. In the subsequent two posts, we will discuss updated pipelines that make RPC calls more efficiently. We begin with illustrating how to manage development resources followed by demonstrating the RPC service that we use in this series. Finally, we develop a Beam pipeline that accesses the external service to augment the input elements.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-08-15-beam-examples-4/featured.png" length="93408" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>