<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Amazon Redshift on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-redshift/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon Redshift on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2026 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-redshift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 1 MSK and Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform. Previously loading data from Kafka into Redshift and Athena usually required Kafka connectors (e.g. Amazon Redshift Sink Connector and Amazon S3 Sink Connector). Recently these AWS services provide features to ingest data from Kafka directly, which facilitates a simpler architecture that achieves low-latency and high-speed ingestion of streaming data. In part 1 of the simplify streaming ingestion on AWS series, we discuss how to develop an end-to-end streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/featured.png" length="32864" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 1 Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on Redshift Serverless. Subsets of IMDb data are used as source and data models are developed in multiple layers according to the dbt best practices.
Part 1 Redshift (this post) Part 2 Glue Part 3 EMR on EC2 Part 4 EMR on EKS Part 5 Athena Motivation In our experience delivering data solutions for our customers, we have observed a desire to move away from a centralised team function, responsible for the data collection, analysis and reporting, towards shifting this responsibility to an organisation&amp;rsquo;s lines of business (LOB) teams.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/featured.png" length="97234" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>