<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>PySpark on Jaehyeon</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/pyspark/</link><description>Recent content in PySpark on Jaehyeon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/pyspark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Remotely Using Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
When we develop a Spark application on EMR, we can use docker for local development or notebooks via EMR Studio (or EMR Notebooks). However, the local development option is not viable if the size of data is large. Also, I am not a fan of notebooks as it is not possible to utilise the features my editor supports such as syntax highlighting, autocomplete and code formatting.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/featured.png" length="72448" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Warehousing ETL Demo with Apache Iceberg on EMR Local Environment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Unlike traditional Data Lake, new table formats (Iceberg, Hudi and Delta Lake) support features that can be used to apply data warehousing patterns, which can bring a way to be rescued from Data Swamp. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to implement ETL using retail analytics data. It has two dimension data (user and product) and a single fact data (order).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/featured.png" length="43604" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Locally Using Docker</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
Amazon EMR is a managed service that simplifies running Apache Spark on AWS. It has multiple deployment options that cover EC2, EKS, Outposts and Serverless. For development and testing, EMR Notebooks or EMR Studio can be an option. Both provide a Jupyter Notebook environment and the former is only available for EMR on EC2. There are cases, however, that development (and learning) is performed in a local environment more efficiently.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/featured.png" length="25693" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Local Development of AWS Glue 3.0 and Later</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
In an earlier post, I demonstrated how to set up a local development environment for AWS Glue 1.0 and 2.0 using a docker image that is published by the AWS Glue team and the Visual Studio Code Remote – Containers extension. Recently AWS Glue 3.0 was released, but a docker image for this version is not published. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate how to create a development environment for AWS Glue 3.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/featured.png" length="30923" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Glue Local Development with Docker and Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</guid><description>This article was originally posted on Tech Insights of Cevo Australia.
As described in the product page, AWS Glue is a serverless data integration service that makes it easy to discover, prepare, and combine data for analytics, machine learning, and application development. For development, a development endpoint is recommended, but it can be costly, inconvenient or unavailable (for Glue 2.0). The AWS Glue team published a Docker image that includes the AWS Glue binaries and all the dependencies packaged together.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/featured.png" length="19535" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>