<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Amazon QuickSight on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-quicksight/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon QuickSight on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2026 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/amazon-quicksight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 5 Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue, EMR on EC2 and EMR on EKS are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/featured.png" length="91796" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 3 EMR on EC2</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless and Glue are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/featured.png" length="91067" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 2 Glue</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. A demo data project that targets Redshift Serverless is illustrated as well. In part 2 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on AWS Glue.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/featured.png" length="90647" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>