<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Apache Beam Python Examples on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/series/apache-beam-python-examples/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Beam Python Examples on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2024 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/series/apache-beam-python-examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Beam Python Examples - Part 2 Calculate Average Word Length with/without Fixed Look back</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-07-18-beam-examples-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-07-18-beam-examples-2/</guid><description>In this post, we develop two Apache Beam pipelines that calculate average word lengths from input texts that are ingested by a Kafka topic. They obtain the statistics in different angles. The first pipeline emits the global average lengths whenever a new input text arrives while the latter triggers those values in a sliding time window.
Part 1 Calculate K Most Frequent Words and Max Word Length Part 2 Calculate Average Word Length with/without Fixed Look back (this post) Part 3 Build Sport Activity Tracker with/without SQL Part 4 Call RPC Service for Data Augmentation Part 5 Call RPC Service in Batch using Stateless DoFn Part 6 Call RPC Service in Batch with Defined Batch Size using Stateful DoFn Part 7 Separate Droppable Data into Side Output Part 8 Enhance Sport Activity Tracker with Runner Motivation Part 9 Develop Batch File Reader and PiSampler using Splittable DoFn Part 10 Develop Streaming File Reader using Splittable DoFn Development Environment The development environment has an Apache Flink cluster and Apache Kafka cluster and gRPC Server - gRPC server will be used in later posts.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-07-18-beam-examples-2/featured.png" length="96924" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Apache Beam Python Examples - Part 1 Calculate K Most Frequent Words and Max Word Length</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-07-04-beam-examples-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-07-04-beam-examples-1/</guid><description>In this series, we develop Apache Beam Python pipelines. The majority of them are from Building Big Data Pipelines with Apache Beam by Jan Lukavský. Mainly relying on the Java SDK, the book teaches fundamentals of Apache Beam using hands-on tasks, and we convert those tasks using the Python SDK. We focus on streaming pipelines, and they are deployed on a local (or embedded) Apache Flink cluster using the Apache Flink Runner.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2024-07-04-beam-examples-1/featured.png" length="96881" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>