<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>AWS on Jaehyeon Kim</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in AWS on Jaehyeon Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023-2023 Jaehyeon Kim. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaehyeon.me/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Pyflink application that reads records from S3 and sends them into a Kafka topic. A custom pipeline Jar file will be created as the Kafka cluster is authenticated by IAM, and it will be demonstrated how to execute the app in a Flink cluster deployed on Docker and locally as a typical Python app. We can assume the S3 data is static metadata that needs to be joined into another stream, and this exercise can be useful for data enrichment.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-11-09-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-3/featured.png" length="138862" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 5 Deploy Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed how to develop a data pipeline from Apache Kafka into OpenSearch locally using Docker. The pipeline will be deployed on AWS using Amazon MSK, Amazon MSK Connect and Amazon OpenSearch Service using Terraform in this post. First the infrastructure will be deployed that covers a Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Virtual Private Network (VPN) server, MSK Cluster and OpenSearch domain. Then Kafka source and sink connectors will be deployed on MSK Connect, followed by performing quick data analysis.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-30-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-5/featured.png" length="85575" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/</guid><description>In this lab, we will create a Kafka producer application using AWS Lambda, which sends fake taxi ride data into a Kafka topic on Amazon MSK. A configurable number of the producer Lambda function will be invoked by an Amazon EventBridge schedule rule. In this way we are able to generate test data concurrently based on the desired volume of messages.
Introduction Lab 1 Produce data to Kafka using Lambda (this post) Lab 2 Write data to Kafka from S3 using Flink Lab 3 Transform and write data to S3 from Kafka using Flink Lab 4 Clean, Aggregate, and Enrich Events with Flink Lab 5 Write data to DynamoDB using Kafka Connect Lab 6 Consume data from Kafka using Lambda [Update 2023-11-06] Initially I planned to deploy Pyflink applications on Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink, but I changed the plan to use a local Flink cluster deployed on Docker.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-26-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-2/featured.png" length="138450" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 4 Develop Aiven OpenSearch Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/</guid><description>OpenSearch is a popular search and analytics engine and its use cases cover log analytics, real-time application monitoring, and clickstream analysis. OpenSearch can be deployed on its own or via Amazon OpenSearch Service. Apache Kafka is a distributed event store and stream-processing platform, and it aims to provide a unified, high-throughput, low-latency platform for handling real-time data feeds. On AWS, Apache Kafka can be deployed via Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-23-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-4/featured.png" length="61820" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Real Time Streaming with Kafka and Flink - Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/</guid><description>Real Time Streaming with Amazon Kinesis is an AWS workshop that helps users build a streaming analytics application on AWS. Incoming events are stored in a number of streams of the Amazon Kinesis Data Streams service, and various other AWS services and tools are used to process and analyse data.
Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform, and it stores incoming events in topics. As part of learning real time streaming analytics on AWS, we can rebuild the analytics applications by replacing the Kinesis streams with Kafka topics.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-10-05-real-time-streaming-with-kafka-and-flink-1/featured.png" length="138141" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 3 Deploy Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/</guid><description>As part of investigating how to utilize Kafka Connect effectively for AWS services integration, I demonstrated how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker in Part 2. Fake order data was generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector was configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table. In this post, I will illustrate how to deploy the data ingestion applications using Amazon MSK and MSK Connect.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-07-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-3/featured.png" length="76240" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 2 Develop Camel DynamoDB Sink Connector</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we reviewed Kafka connectors focusing on AWS services integration. Among the available connectors, the suite of Apache Camel Kafka connectors and the Kinesis Kafka connector from the AWS Labs can be effective for building data ingestion pipelines on AWS. In this post, I will illustrate how to develop the Camel DynamoDB sink connector using Docker. Fake order data will be generated using the MSK Data Generator source connector, and the sink connector will be configured to consume the topic messages to ingest them into a DynamoDB table.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-06-04-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-2/featured.png" length="87044" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Kafka Connect for AWS Services Integration - Part 1 Introduction</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/</guid><description>Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK) are two managed streaming services offered by AWS. Many resources on the web indicate Kinesis Data Streams is better when it comes to integrating with AWS services. However, it is not necessarily the case with the help of Kafka Connect. According to the documentation of Apache Kafka, Kafka Connect is a tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-05-03-kafka-connect-for-aws-part-1/featured.png" length="22272" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Integrate Glue Schema Registry with Your Python Kafka App</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/</guid><description>As Kafka producer and consumer apps are decoupled, they operate on Kafka topics rather than communicating with each other directly. As described in the Confluent document, Schema Registry provides a centralized repository for managing and validating schemas for topic message data, and for serialization and deserialization of the data over the network. Producers and consumers to Kafka topics can use schemas to ensure data consistency and compatibility as schemas evolve. In AWS, the Glue Schema Registry supports features to manage and enforce schemas on data streaming applications using convenient integrations with Apache Kafka, Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and AWS Lambda.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-04-12-integrate-glue-schema-registry/featured.png" length="46040" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 2 MSK and Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/</guid><description>In Part 1, we discussed a streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless. Athena provides the MSK connector to enable SQL queries on Apache Kafka topics directly, and it can also facilitate the extraction of insights without setting up an additional pipeline to store data into S3. In this post, we discuss how to update the streaming ingestion solution so that data in the Kafka topic can be queried by Athena instead of Redshift.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-03-14-simplify-streaming-ingestion-athena/featured.png" length="43403" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Streaming Ingestion on AWS – Part 1 MSK and Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/</guid><description>Apache Kafka is a popular distributed event store and stream processing platform. Previously loading data from Kafka into Redshift and Athena usually required Kafka connectors (e.g. Amazon Redshift Sink Connector and Amazon S3 Sink Connector). Recently these AWS services provide features to ingest data from Kafka directly, which facilitates a simpler architecture that achieves low-latency and high-speed ingestion of streaming data. In part 1 of the simplify streaming ingestion on AWS series, we discuss how to develop an end-to-end streaming ingestion solution using EventBridge, Lambda, MSK and Redshift Serverless on AWS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2023-02-08-simplify-streaming-ingestion-redshift/featured.png" length="32864" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 5 Athena</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue, EMR on EC2 and EMR on EKS are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-12-06-dbt-on-aws-part-5-athena/featured.png" length="91796" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 4 EMR on EKS</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless, Glue and EMR on EC2 are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-11-01-dbt-on-aws-part-4-emr-eks/featured.png" length="91067" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 3 EMR on EC2</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In the previous posts, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. Demo data projects that target Redshift Serverless and Glue are illustrated as well.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-19-dbt-on-aws-part-3-emr-ec2/featured.png" length="91067" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 2 Glue</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1, we discussed benefits of a common data transformation tool and the potential of dbt to cover a wide range of data projects from data warehousing to data lake to data lakehouse. A demo data project that targets Redshift Serverless is illustrated as well. In part 2 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on AWS Glue.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-10-09-dbt-on-aws-part-2-glue/featured.png" length="90647" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Build Tool (dbt) for Effective Data Transformation on AWS – Part 1 Redshift</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/</guid><description>The data build tool (dbt) is an effective data transformation tool and it supports key AWS analytics services - Redshift, Glue, EMR and Athena. In part 1 of the dbt on AWS series, we discuss data transformation pipelines using dbt on Redshift Serverless. Subsets of IMDb data are used as source and data models are developed in multiple layers according to the dbt best practices.
Part 1 Redshift (this post) Part 2 Glue Part 3 EMR on EC2 Part 4 EMR on EKS Part 5 Athena Motivation In our experience delivering data solutions for our customers, we have observed a desire to move away from a centralised team function, responsible for the data collection, analysis and reporting, towards shifting this responsibility to an organisation&amp;rsquo;s lines of business (LOB) teams.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-28-dbt-on-aws-part-1-redshift/featured.png" length="97234" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Remotely Using Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/</guid><description>When we develop a Spark application on EMR, we can use docker for local development or notebooks via EMR Studio (or EMR Notebooks). However, the local development option is not viable if the size of data is large. Also, I am not a fan of notebooks as it is not possible to utilise the features my editor supports such as syntax highlighting, autocomplete and code formatting. Moreover, it is not possible to organise code into modules and to perform unit testing properly with that option.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-09-07-emr-remote-dev/featured.png" length="72448" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Manage EMR on EKS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/</guid><description>Amazon EMR on EKS is a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on EKS. While eksctl is popular for working with Amazon EKS clusters, it has limitations when it comes to building infrastructure that integrates multiple AWS services. Also, it is not straightforward to update EKS cluster resources incrementally with it. On the other hand Terraform can be an effective tool for managing infrastructure that includes not only EKS and EMR virtual clusters but also other AWS resources.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-26-emr-on-eks-with-terraform/featured.png" length="67936" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Revisit AWS Lambda Invoke Function Operator of Apache Airflow</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular workflow management platform. A wide range of AWS services are integrated with the platform by Amazon AWS Operators. AWS Lambda is one of the integrated services, and it can be used to develop workflows efficiently. The current Lambda Operator, however, just invokes a Lambda function, and it can fail to report the invocation result of a function correctly and to record the exact error message from failure.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-08-06-revisit-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="24814" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Application Model (SAM) for Data Professionals</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-07-18-sam-for-data-professionals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-07-18-sam-for-data-professionals/</guid><description>AWS Lambda provides serverless computing capabilities, and it can be used for performing validation or light processing/transformation of data. Moreover, with its integration with more than 140 AWS services, it facilitates building complex systems employing event-driven architectures. There are many ways to build serverless applications and one of the most efficient ways is using specialised frameworks such as the AWS Serverless Application Model (SAM) and Serverless Framework. In this post, I’ll demonstrate how to build a serverless data processing application using SAM.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-07-18-sam-for-data-professionals/featured.png" length="22838" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Warehousing ETL Demo with Apache Iceberg on EMR Local Environment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/</guid><description>Unlike traditional Data Lake, new table formats (Iceberg, Hudi and Delta Lake) support features that can be used to apply data warehousing patterns, which can bring a way to be rescued from Data Swamp. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to implement ETL using retail analytics data. It has two dimension data (user and product) and a single fact data (order). The dimension data sets have different ETL strategies depending on whether to track historical changes.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-06-26-iceberg-etl-demo/featured.png" length="43604" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Develop and Test Apache Spark Apps for EMR Locally Using Docker</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/</guid><description>Amazon EMR is a managed service that simplifies running Apache Spark on AWS. It has multiple deployment options that cover EC2, EKS, Outposts and Serverless. For development and testing, EMR Notebooks or EMR Studio can be an option. Both provide a Jupyter Notebook environment and the former is only available for EMR on EC2. There are cases, however, that development (and learning) is performed in a local environment more efficiently. The AWS Glue team understands this demand, and they illustrate how to make use of a custom Docker image for Glue in a recent blog post.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-05-08-emr-local-dev/featured.png" length="25693" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 2 MSK Deployment</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution with a schema registry. A local development environment is set up using Docker Compose. The Debezium and Confluent S3 connectors are deployed with the Confluent Avro converter and the Apicurio registry is used as the schema registry service. A quick example is shown to illustrate how schema evolution can be managed by the schema registry. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll build the solution on AWS using MSK, MSK Connect, Aurora PostgreSQL and ECS.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-04-03-schema-registry-part2/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Use External Schema Registry with MSK Connect – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/</guid><description>When we discussed a Change Data Capture (CDC) solution in one of the earlier posts, we used the JSON converter that comes with Kafka Connect. We optionally enabled the key and value schemas and the topic messages include those schemas together with payload. It seems to be convenient at first as the messages are saved into S3 on their own. However, it became cumbersome when we tried to use the DeltaStreamer utility.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-03-07-schema-registry-part1/featured.png" length="59689" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Simplify Your Development on AWS with Terraform</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/</guid><description>When I wrote my data lake demo series (part 1, part 2 and part 3) recently, I used an Aurora PostgreSQL, MSK and EMR cluster. All of them were deployed to private subnets and dedicated infrastructure was created using CloudFormation. Using the infrastructure as code (IaC) tool helped a lot, but it resulted in creating 7 CloudFormation stacks, which was a bit harder to manage in the end. Then I looked into how to simplify building infrastructure and managing resources on AWS and decided to use Terraform instead.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-02-06-dev-infra-terraform/featured.png" length="46253" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>EMR on EKS by Example</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/</guid><description>EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to automate the provisioning and management of open-source big data frameworks on Amazon EKS. While a wide range of open source big data components are available in EMR on EC2, only Apache Spark is available in EMR on EKS. It is more flexible, however, that applications of different EMR versions can be run in multiple availability zones on either EC2 or Fargate.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2022-01-17-emr-on-eks-by-example/featured.png" length="76740" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Lake Demo using Change Data Capture (CDC) on AWS – Part 3 Implement Data Lake</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-19-datalake-demo-part3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-19-datalake-demo-part3/</guid><description>In the previous post, we created a VPC that has private and public subnets in 2 availability zones in order to build and deploy the data lake solution on AWS. NAT instances are created to forward outbound traffic to the internet and a VPN bastion host is set up to facilitate deployment. An Aurora PostgreSQL cluster is deployed to host the source database and a Python command line app is used to create the database.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-19-datalake-demo-part3/featured.png" length="164526" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Lake Demo using Change Data Capture (CDC) on AWS – Part 2 Implement CDC</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-12-datalake-demo-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-12-datalake-demo-part2/</guid><description>In the previous post, we discussed a data lake solution where data ingestion is performed using change data capture (CDC) and the output files are upserted to an Apache Hudi table. Being registered to Glue Data Catalog, it can be used for ad-hoc queries and report/dashboard creation. The Northwind database is used as the source database and, following the transactional outbox pattern, order-related changes are _upserted _to an outbox table by triggers.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-12-datalake-demo-part2/featured.png" length="164526" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Data Lake Demo using Change Data Capture (CDC) on AWS – Part 1 Local Development</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-05-datalake-demo-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-05-datalake-demo-part1/</guid><description>Change data capture (CDC) is a proven data integration pattern that has a wide range of applications. Among those, data replication to data lakes is a good use case in data engineering. Coupled with best-in-breed data lake formats such as Apache Hudi, we can build an efficient data replication solution. This is the first post of the data lake demo series. Over time, we&amp;rsquo;ll build a data lake that uses CDC.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-12-05-datalake-demo-part1/featured.png" length="164526" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Local Development of AWS Glue 3.0 and Later</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/</guid><description>In an earlier post, I demonstrated how to set up a local development environment for AWS Glue 1.0 and 2.0 using a docker image that is published by the AWS Glue team and the Visual Studio Code Remote – Containers extension. Recently AWS Glue 3.0 was released, but a docker image for this version is not published. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate how to create a development environment for AWS Glue 3.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-11-14-glue-3-local-development/featured.png" length="30923" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Glue Local Development with Docker and Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/</guid><description>As described in the product page, AWS Glue is a serverless data integration service that makes it easy to discover, prepare, and combine data for analytics, machine learning, and application development. For development, a development endpoint is recommended, but it can be costly, inconvenient or unavailable (for Glue 2.0). The AWS Glue team published a Docker image that includes the AWS Glue binaries and all the dependencies packaged together. After inspecting it, I find some modifications are necessary in order to build a development environment on it.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2021-08-20-glue-local-development/featured.png" length="19535" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Thoughts on Apache Airflow AWS Lambda Operator</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/</guid><description>Apache Airflow is a popular open-source workflow management platform. Typically tasks run remotely by Celery workers for scalability. In AWS, however, scalability can also be achieved using serverless computing services in a simpler way. For example, the ECS Operator allows to run dockerized tasks and, with the Fargate launch type, they can run in a serverless environment.
The ECS Operator alone is not sufficient because it can take up to several minutes to pull a Docker image and to set up network interface (for the case of Fargate launch type).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2020-04-13-airflow-lambda-operator/featured.png" length="44994" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>AWS Local Development with LocalStack</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/</guid><description>LocalStack provides an easy-to-use test/mocking framework for developing AWS applications. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to utilize LocalStack for development using a web service.
Specifically a simple web service built with Flask-RestPlus is used. It supports simple CRUD operations against a database table. It is set that SQS and Lambda are used for creating and updating a record. When a POST or PUT request is made, the service sends a message to a SQS queue and directly returns 204 reponse.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2019-07-20-aws-localstack/featured.png" length="164886" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part IV - Serving R ML Model via S3</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/</guid><description>In the previous posts, it is discussed how to package/deploy an R model with AWS Lambda and to expose the Lambda function via Amazon API Gateway. Main benefits of serverless architecture is cost-effectiveness and being hassle-free from provisioning/managing servers. While the API returns a predicted admission status value given GRE, GPA and Rank, there is an issue if it is served within a web application: Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS). This post discusses how to resolve this issue by updating API configuration and the Lambda function handler with a simple web application.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-17-serverless-data-product-4/featured.png" length="225463" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part III - Exposing R ML Model via APIG</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/</guid><description>In Part I of this series, R and necessary libraries/packages together with a Lambda function handler are packaged and saved to Amazon S3. Then, in Part II, the package is deployed at AWS Lambda after creating and assigning a role to the Lambda function. Although the Lambda function can be called via the Invoke API, it&amp;rsquo;ll be much more useful if the function can be called as a web service (or API).</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-13-serverless-data-product-3/featured.png" length="173293" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part II - Deploying R ML Model via Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/</guid><description>In the previous post, serverless event-driven application development is introduced. Also how to package R, necessary libraries/packages and a Lambda function handler is discussed. No need of provisioning/managing servers is one of the key benefits of the architecture. It is also a cost-effective way of delivering a data product as functions are executed on-demand rather than in servers that run 24/7. Furthermore AWS Lambda free tier includes 1M free requests per month and 400,000 GB-seconds of compute time per month, which is available to both existing and new AWS customers indefinitely.</description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-11-serverless-data-product-2/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item><item><title>Serverless Data Product POC Backend Part I - Packaging R ML Model for Lambda</title><link>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[Let say you&rsquo;ve got a prediction model built in R and you&rsquo;d like to productionize it, for example, by serving it in a web application. One way is exposing the model through an API that returns the predicted result as a web service. However there are many issues. Firstly R is not a language for API development although there may be some ways - eg the plumber package. More importantly developing an API is not the end of the story as the API can&rsquo;t be served in a production system if it is not deployed/managed/upgraded/patched/&hellip; appropriately in a server or if it is not scalable, protected via authentication/authorization and so on.]]></description><enclosure url="https://jaehyeon.me/blog/2017-04-08-serverless-data-product-1/featured.png" length="139725" type="image/png"/></item></channel></rss>